Hey, hey, hey.
Heat.
Hello, good evening and good day
everybody and welcome back to the Ask
Abij show. Today we are doing episode
328. I hope everyone is doing great and
today I'm going to discuss uh
geopolitics as well as history. I'm
going to take questions that you have
asked in the comments with the hash
askit. But before we get into that let's
see who all is there on the live chat
live with us. I can see Nick Hill Sagnik
Achara. Sign Acharia once again drawing
sack 53282
geopolitical dub is here from Ind. Good
evening sir. really loud Miss Patel.
Namaste
Jamiha J7E
Tanmadesh Pandi Tanmadesh Pandi Casta
Jana 6537
Sachin Yadav is watching live after a
long time. Welcome back Sachin G to have
you sir. Brave robot says meow meow.
Swami 0709 Surya Prattab is here from
Kolinga. Namaskar G. Namaskar Rahul
Dunak Namaskar G. Danesh Pand brave
robot daran Patil namaste gatya
patriotic namaskar shri
sham shri nam 3290 hello dik shrian
namaste really now Miss Patel once again
Anand P's birthday well happy birthday
to you Anandpai I wish you the best uh
many happy returns of the day and the
best of luck swami is here from Jaipur
good evening uh sana satish zero 905.
Hello Dank Ashish Chabra. Namaste G. Mac
4 G1U. Namaste. Dash. Namaste. Mishra.
Hello. Good to see you. Swami says, "Do
have I watched Braveheart? I have
watched a long time ago." Rishi Das
Gupta. Uhuk live. King Ritik Brave
robot. Pratik Pratik Pachi. Hello. Abai
Singh. Abai Singh Vihang Kuran. King
Ritik the Great. Dashan Patel Raguir.
Rair Singh. Ujual Aravsha humanity
survives. Abai Singh Ash King Ganymede
from Marwar uncertainty principle.
Ganesh sager atwa y1s brown leprechaun.
Uh Laksh dangi.
Who else do we have? Ujal is here from
Assam. Good evening. Sujit Shana Gandh.
Good evening. Arav Singh. Uh SKR7733
is here from Dhaka India. Well, good to
see you. Good to have you. Bibbe
Chakraarti, Sesh Nal, Raguir Singh,
Suresh, Siatch, Agni, Vana, Omikar,
hello. Good to see you. Hershel, Jooshi,
uh, Rishih,
Kuba, Sad,
um, Hyphen is here. Hershel, Jooshi,
Agni, Vana, Pascar Bandit, hello. Kahan
is here from Delhi. Rahul Dunaka once
again and Kamal Parashar is here from
Merritt. Ankitakab good evening ma'am
good to see you. Kahan is here from once
again Delhi and everyone else. Okay.
Okay. That is enough of greeting
everybody individually. I greet you all
collectively. Thank you so much for
being on the live chat. Vikram as well
and everyone else. Okay. So let's get
going with the questions. Plenty of
questions, plenty of concern about how
things are going these days. So where
shall we begin? Shall we begin with the
India US trade agreement trade deal? The
supposed trade deal. Shall we deal with
Shall we begin with Epstein? Let's begin
with Epstein.
So what is the deal with this person?
Right. The question is this. The
question is by Rushab T. And Rushab T is
super concerned about the Epstein files.
I mean it's a very big development that
we are seeing in the world in the United
States. So the question is what are the
Epstein files? Who was this evil and
lowest man in humanity named Jeffrey
Epstein? Many American elites like Bill
Gates, Elon Musk, the Clintons, Howard
Lutnik, that fella, um various actors,
various entertainers, musicians,
scientists, and God knows who else are
named in this in these files. Even
Donald J. Trump and his family. The
details coming out are horrific to say
the least.
So if these files reveal such a dirty
truth, why were they released? Do these
files have any link with geopolitics or
do they symbolize more of the internal
decay of the United States? Right? First
of all, who who was this person Jeffrey
Epstein? Is he I mean who was he? If it
is a was if it's a past tense. So
Jeffrey Epstein was an American
financier whatever that means. and he
was a convicted uh sex offender. Okay,
this fellow Epstein, he ran
a network of trafficking of of women, of
trafficking of underage girls, of
various kinds of horrific exploitation
and abuse of human beings. And Epstein
was a very wealthy person and he used
his wealth, his properties, his islands
and his ranches and his houses and he
used his social connections
to recruit
victims and to abuse victims. And he was
first convicted I think in 2008 or 2009
um on on charges related to procuring a
minor person for um for nasty stuff.
Okay, that sort of thing. And he was
also indicted for I think sexual sex
trafficking or something in 2019. So he
was a person with a long track record of
being a horrific person but a very
well-connected horrific person and a
very wealthy person and he had the he
his friends were the who's who of the
United States professors Noam Chomsky is
involved in the Epstein files and you
know politicians ex-presidents uh
international
you know world leaders uh Deepak Chopra
that that hypocrite that charlatan who
pretends to be a Hindu but who's
actually a converted Christian that guy
um you have film stars you have all
kinds of people on this you have Elon
Musk you don't have Joe Rogan apparently
you don't have Charlie Sheen would you
believe it and so on so that's Jeffrey
Epstein and he is said to have died in
prison in the year 2019 apparently a
suicide and very few people supposedly
believe that in the US let's put one
cares right so so that is Jeffrey
Epstein now his right-hand person was
his uh I don't know girlfriend I suppose
Jizlain Gizlane Gileain Maxwell so she
is a British citizen she was Epstein's
right man right-hand man or right-hand
person who was his chief facilitator his
chief fixer she helped Epstein recruit
and groom and traffic underage girls and
various kinds of victims girls, boys,
whatever. And she was arrested in 2020,
the year after Epstein supposedly died.
And uh she was also found guilty of the
same kind of offenses that Epstein was
found guilty of. And she is currently in
prison. I don't know how long the prison
sentence is. You can look it up, but she
has been sentenced to prison for her
role in whatever Epstein was doing. So
that is Epstein. That is his right-hand
man or woman, uh Gileain Maxwell. Now
what are these Epste epstein files,
right? Is it one one one one sing single
document? It's not a single document.
It's a whole bunch of different kinds of
documents. You have FBI reports. You
have US Department of Justice reports
and records from multiple investigations
into Jeffrey Epste and the people around
him. So what kind of documents do we
have in the um in the Epson files? You
have uh various kinds of evidence. Okay.
uh legally admissible potentially
evidence from various investigations.
There are the returns from search
warrants. There are seized physical
items. There are uh transcripts of
interviews and summaries of interviews
of various people. There are
photographs. There are videos. There's
electronic data. There are court
records. There are flight logs from
Epstein's private jets, private planes.
Okay. Um there are logs and records
related to the people who came and went
from his private island. There is
Epstein's contact book. There are there
are all the emails that Epstein
received. There are all the emails that
Epstein sent. There are financial
documents. There are um witness
statements. There are statements from
victims with pseudonyms. Um there's
evidence connected to Epstein's
residences, Epstein's properties.
There's all these different kinds of
overlapping sets of materials. Okay. Uh
there are files from F FBI
investigations. There are files from the
US attorney's office case files. There
are uh civil case records. There are
materials from grand juries and there
are prison custody records and god knows
what kind of information. All kinds of
records. All of this collectively info.
All this information collectively which
supposedly runs into millions of
documents. All of this together is the
Epstein files. And the US government has
been going through these files and
redacting files you know obfiscating or
hiding information putting black marks
over over names and whatnot uh
supposedly to uh uh protect victims and
people who have not been charged with
crimes. So people whose names are if
they are redacted they are either
victims or apparently they are people
who are not actually charged with any uh
crimes. So they may look bad in the in
the documents
but they have not been officially
charged with crimes. That's why their
names are redacted. That's what the US
government says. So only some portions
of the Epstein files have been released
to the public under court orders. Okay.
Um
and um so it say it is said that about 3
million or so documents have been
released and they are available online
with a lot of redactions and apparently
at least 3 million documents more exist
if if not more than that and those have
not been released to the public yet. So
that is the Epstein files. All of this
stuff put together and a lot of people
are saying that the you know the
redactions they they actually uh protect
not just the victims but also some of
the offenders apparently it looks like
um and that sort of thing. So that is
the deal that is the Epstein files. So
Epstein was he the evilst person in
humanity the lowest person in humanity?
Not by a long shot. Epstein was simply a
servant. Epstein was just a guy
who who played a small role in the
activities of the rich and powerful in
the US. He simply helped them get what
they wanted. Epstein was well he was in
prison in 2019. Apparently he died in
2019 before the coh co thing started.
Right.
But these elites, these American rich
and powerful people, they have these
proclivities for the more costliest
things. So after Epstein was jailed and
eventually he supposedly died,
who has been providing what they need is
the question. Do you think there was
only one Jeffrey Epstein? Do you think
there's no one around today who does the
same things? So Epstein wasn't the
lowest and evilst person in humanity.
His clients
were the lowest and evilst people in
human existence.
Okay, his clients are the evilst people.
Jeffrey Epstein is just a tool that they
used and there are allegations that he
was linked to this government agency or
that intelligence agency or whatever. Uh
we don't know how true or false these
claims are. Some of those could be
plausible. Some of those could be well
maybe speculation. I I would not want to
speculate.
I'm sure there is some kind of truth to
some of these things potentially. I
don't know. Um
so if these files reveal such a dirty
truth, why were the released? Well,
court orders apparently. H
and maybe it was time to throw some
people under the bus. Perhaps maybe the
US establishment has decided that. Maybe
it was time to pressurize some very
powerful individuals. For example, the
president of the United States, Donald
J. Trump. Maybe it was time to
pressurize him because one of the major
figures whose name apparently figures
hundreds maybe thousands of times in the
files is Donald Trump.
He seems to be all over the place. Elon
Musk also is there. He figures in that.
Nam Chsky, the great leftist professor,
intellectual, he figures in that. And
there's so many names. So many names.
Um, so why were these files released? So
like I said, maybe it's time to the US
establishment decided that maybe some of
these older people who are no longer
relevant but who are still hogging the
limelight and they still have this sense
of importance. Let's throw them under
the bus and let's now behind the scenes
promote newer people perhaps. Maybe
that's the thing. Maybe it's about
pressurizing some people who are still
in power like Donald J. Trump. Um,
one can only speculate why these were
released right now. The other question
is that these files were released, these
documents were released by the Trump
administration.
Sure, under the c under the orders of
the courts or whatever, but how can the
Trump administration released these
files that have Trump's name all over
the place? Is Trump no longer in control
of his administration? Does somebody
else control his administration? These
are interesting questions that crop up
as a consequence of the release of these
files. Do these files have any link with
geopolitics? Oh yes they do in a variety
of ways. Um they do symbolize the
internal de of the US. They do symbolize
the truth of the kind of
people who rule the world in the United
States.
So you the United States it's clear that
their rich and powerful people are all
apparently many of them are pedophiles.
Many of them are absolute utter depraved
people. Many of them are are
absolute monsters. Maybe the United
States should be renamed Pedo Filistan.
So we now understand the US a little bit
better. A nation that is founded on
genocide and slavery and now it is a
land of pedophiles.
And they like to lecture the world about
morality and human rights and democracy.
But their truth is that they are ruled
by pedophiles and perverts and criminals
and cannibals.
Looks like all the conspiracy theories
that people have been speaking about all
looks like all of these conspiracy
theories are true. Looks like pizza gate
is true. Looks like all these
most outlandish conspiracy theories
looks like they are all true.
So the worst things you could have
imagined about the United States and the
people who run the United States,
thousands of people, looks like all the
all of the worst things we could imagine
are true. That's the kind of country
this this nation is.
So yeah, clearly internal decay of the
US. I mean this is western culture, my
friends. This is American culture. The
people who run the United States, they
have a different set of rules that apply
to them. Essentially, no rules, no laws
apply to them, laws only apply to the
rank and file American,
right? So laws don't apply to the rich
and powerful in the US. And these people
their culture which stems back to
European culture. Well, this is the
culture. Cannibalism
abusing and exploiting helpless children
and babies. Cannibalism, pedophilia. I
mean, this is their culture.
I mean, it's it's horrific to read about
this. It's horrific to look into this.
Absolutely ghastly.
Harsh Kajula says if Epstein was as
influential and connected as he was and
every other famous person well
apparently has been to his island and
done whatever they do they did there
then why was only Epstein caught and why
was he the person that allegedly died in
prison? Why was no one else prosecuted?
Why did only Epstein get convicted in
the first place considering everyone
else was in on it? Well, that's a great
question. Was Epstein the fall guy? Was
all the blame was all all the blame
thrown on the shoulders of Epstein and
was it taken out
in order to absorb everybody else? I
mean you have the names of all these
people that figure so
so incredibly repeatedly in the Epstein
files. What about these people? Why have
they not been prosecuted? Why have they
not been imprisoned or jailed or
whatever? Why are these people still out
there? Rich and famous and powerful
people. Bill Gates, the kind of things
that are being said about Bill Gates.
Good god.
Why are all these people out there? The
kind of things you read on in random
documents. It's the most
horrific stuff that you can that you can
imagine. It's like things out of a
horror movie. So why are the other
people not imprisoned? Why are they not
uh why has no action been taken against
them? Well, I suppose we don't know
which of the this see these Epstein file
documents they are of various kinds of
various types of documents. How many of
these documents constitute legally
admissible evidence?
How many of these documents are not
legally admissible? And uh if even if
the documents exist, do they actually
constitute proof of guilt or proof of
whatever? So that only lawyers can tell
you, right? Um
it looks like nobody's going to be
prosecuted. Looks like that. Looks like
everybody's going to go away scot-free.
Only Epstein is going to be the fall
guy. That sort of thing. It looks like
that. Um so the US legal system and
every legal system in the world, it
protects the rich and the powerful.
Okay, not every but almost every legal
system in the world protects the rich
and the powerful. Okay,
I'm sure you are all familiar with
various kinds of legal systems in
various countries. Look around, look at
there's something that's said on paper
and that's that's there's another thing
that is like the way the system actually
works and you'll find that very often in
many countries the legal system actually
serves and protects the rich and the
powerful and victimizes the poor and the
ordinary person. So I suppose the US
also seems to be this sort of thing and
that's why Epstein has been all the
blame has been thrown on Epstein. He has
been vilified, demonized. I'm not saying
he was good. He was a monster. No, no
doubt about the fact that Epstein was an
absolute depraved person of an absolute
monster. So they did decided that he's
clearly a guy who clearly is a monster.
So let's put all the blame on him and
let's try and get everybody else off the
hook per perhaps. I don't think I don't
see anybody else, you know, at this
point in time being uh prosecuted or put
into prison. I mean, nobody has been
this hasn't happened with anybody else
thus far, right?
Uh and how did Epstein get convicted in
the first place? Uh you I'm not sure
what the details are. The first
conviction, the first time he was
charged with whatever was in 2008,
wasn't it? So he was charged in 2008 on
um traffic trafficking of a minor or
something right and eventually he was
indicted in 2019. So 11 years after the
first thing first time so all the people
who were corresponding with Epstein in
2010 11 12 13 14 15 16 all the way to
2019 these people knew that he's a
convicted
sex offender who
is known for exploiting underage victims
and all that and still they were happy
to to go to his island to go to his
mansions and his ranches and his farm
houses or whatever get on his flight on
his jet planes. They knew what kind of
person he was and yet nobody is being
prosecuted. So that's the United States
for you. Maybe will someone be
prosecuted in the future? Well, it
depends. We'll see. We'll see about
that. But right now it's only epste even
though everyone else's name has come
out. Howard Lutnik.
Howard Lutnik. Trump's Trump's minion.
The guy who keeps on disparaging India.
That creep. I mean see see his
involvement in the Epstein files. H
okay
Gorov says after seeing some of the
leaked conversations especially Mr.
Hardep Singh Puri convincing trying to
convince Epste and other people to
invest in India do you think Epstein
might be part of the deep state and now
the deep state is pulling the Trump the
strings of Donald J. Trump by leaking
all this in order to do something more
favorable. Okay. About Hardep Singhpuri,
Minister Hardep Singhpuri. So there are
one or two documents in the files that
have a mention or mentions of Mr. Hardep
Singhpuri. And if you read the document,
you will see that Mr. Hardep Singhpuri
is trying to pitch make in India
to Epstein and his associates. I am not
sure if Mr. Hardip Singhpuri even knew
what kind of person Epstein was. Let's
say he knew but let's say potentially
that he Mr. Hardp Singh Puri in 2014 may
perhaps have known what kind of person
Epstein is that he was convicted of
whatever whatever
but it was clear that Epstein was a
highly powerful highly connected person
in the US he knew everybody
right so he's one guy the point person
for getting out reaching out to everyone
in the US why not use that doesn't the
US
use dictators all over the world the
Americans know that these dictators are
monsters and still they use the
dictators to serve America's national
interests. I suppose from that
perspective it was fine for Mr. Hadib
Singh Puri to reach out to Epstein and
ask Epstein to reach out to other people
on India's behalf and give a give this
entire you know outline of what make
India is and what Prime Minister Modi's
vision for India is that was completely
above board there's nothing dirty or
whatever in it so Mr. Mr. Harip Singh
Puri his involvement is clearly
something that's in line with India's
national interest. So yeah there's
nothing you know unward about that
I mean that's the one clean interaction
we see in the Epstein files Mr. Singuri
going and saying make it India please
invest that sort of thing. Um now could
Epstein have been part of the deep
state? Clearly, whatever the deep state
is, if it is the unelected powerful
people who who essentially own and
operate and run the US, well, Epstein
was very much involved with all of them.
No question about that. Yeah. So,
Epstein was an agent or or a member or
some kind of servant of the deep state.
If somebody knew who what the deep state
is, Epstein Epstein clearly most likely
knew what the deep state is and who the
people are. Um, now that the deep side
is pulling Trump's strength of Donald
Trump by leaking all of this in order to
do something more favorable.
Yeah, possibly, possibly, possibly,
maybe pressure. So, Epstein definitely
knew what the deep state is and who the
members of the deep state are for sure.
Was he a part of the deep state? No, he
was just a tool of the deep state.
Okay, three questions about once again
Epstein. Brian Kasiwis says, "Given the
recent Epstein file leaks, ongoing legal
controversies, tax frauds and falling
approval ratings around Donald Trump. Do
you see a real risk of political ouster
of Trump does this signal a rupture
between Trump and the US deep state?"
Sum Pramanic says, "We all know what has
come out of the Epstein files. It looks
like the US deep state is using the
Epstein files as a pressure point to
pressurize certain powerful persons
around the world. What's my thoughts on
the matter?" Real Vladimir Putin says
Israel wants to do a regime change in
Iran. For that they will need US help.
Is this Epstein files release which
includes Trump also a way to pressurize
Trump in attacking Iran? So real Putin
seems to be implying potentially that
Israel controls a lot of things in the
US and Israel has had these Epstein
files released. Well, I don't know about
that.
Uh does does this signal a rupture
between the deep state and Trump? Um
is the deep state using the Epstein
files as as a pressure point to
pressurize powerful people? Definitely.
See what is the deep state? First of
all, something I've spoken about in the
past. Obviously, I don't know what the
deep state is and who the members of the
deep state are. But typically in every
nation there is an unelected
extrademocratic extra electoral power
center of powerful people who are who
remain in power and who essentially to a
certain extent control what happens in
the country from behind the scenes and
you can't remove them democratically or
electorally. It's an unelected power
center. So you have such power centers
in most countries. In the United States
also you it's clear you have something
like that. It could be the unelected
establishment. It could be a bunch of
150 very powerful men who may not all be
Americans, whatever. So you have
something called the deep state for
sure. It may be the unelected
bureaucracy. Maybe it's a tool of these
people possibly. Now, is there a rupture
between Trump and the deep state? I
don't think there's a rupture between
Trump and the deep state. Maybe the deep
state wants to push Trump to do
something. Maybe maybe incentivize him
more to do something. maybe give him a
bit of pressure so that he is a little
more proactive in doing what they want.
I think Trump is very much in line with
whatever the deep state wants. He is
their primary tool right now. He's their
most visible tool. So Trump would not
have come to power if he was not aligned
with the objectives and agendas of the
deep state. And what he's doing right
now is carrying out the the agenda of
the deep state clearly. So there's no as
far as I can see there is no raptor
between the deep state and Trump but
maybe Trump isn't able to achieve
certain results that they would like to
be achieved and maybe they are just you
know giving him some extra incentive
extra motivation to get something done
is it is it is Israel also involved in
the deep state well I can't say I don't
know for I I don't know obviously um
does the deep state want a regime change
in Iran and is Trump dragging his feet
on that? Well, that's a possibility, but
I I obviously would not know for sure
because I am not in the deep state. I
don't know who's who the the people are.
I can only speculate. Uh so definitely
pressure on Trump. I don't think there's
a rupture. Uh the the Epstein files can
definitely be used to pressurize not
just Trump but even other people, even
other world leaders who uh whose names
may have been leaked or revealed in the
Epson files. So definitely uh it's it's
uh something that can that can be used
to pressurize various powerful people
around the world, various politicians,
various uh world leaders, various
business people and so on and so forth.
Definitely. um Israel I don't know can't
say
really now Miss Patel says I recently
read about the tophets and child
sacrifice ritual of Carthage and the
Canonites
in Jerusalem so in Carthage you have the
Phoenicians
in the canonites are near Jerusalem
horrific 20,000 erns found related to
the so-called gods Bal in Malik is it
okay to ask about
Also we know of human sacrifice in our
culture in India but who exactly were
chosen for that? I have not found any
evidence of children being involved in
human sacrifice in India. Can you
confirm it? I hope all the coconuts were
adults. Okay.
To
so there was this
so
this place called Carthage. It had this
cemeteryl-l like thing which was called
a toph. The tophet, this word topheet is
actually a word that is used I think in
the Jewish Bible, the Hebrew Bible. And
it talks about a people called the
Canonites who used to live in the
Israel, Palestine, um, Lebanon, that
region, today's that region. And there
was this place near Jerusalem where the
Canonites conducted these horrific
alleged rituals in which they would pass
children through fire to sacrifice these
children to a god that was called Malik
in the Hebrew Bible. Now this god Malik,
it probably is a euphemism for some
other god. Maybe it is one of the bal
gods. Maybe it is Yahweh even. We don't
know for sure. So this this this entity
called Malok is the focus of these
allegations in the Hebrew Bible of these
horrific practices of passing children
through fire to propitiate the god or
gods or whatever. And it was the
Canaanites who were a people who lived
in in this region in the Israel
Palestine
Liban region. They are the ones who are
alleged to have been practitioners of
child sacrifice. Now the Konites they
kind of were ancestrally related to the
later people called the Phoenicians and
the Phoenicians are the people who who
lived in Carthage right Punic people the
Phoenicians and Carthage is North Africa
so let's let's go to the map do we have
a map yes we have a map so so let me now
talk about the regions that we are
talking about okay
uh because we're dealing with talking
about Jeffrey Epstein and all so let's
look at the matter from a historical
perspective as well. So when we talk
about uh when we talk about the Canonite
people, okay, we talking about people
who lived in this region uh Israel,
Palestine um you know Palestine is
obviously not a country but whatever and
Lebanon and uh the coastal region of
Syria and even the western parts of
Jordan all of this this is called the
what is it called? It's called Yeah.
Yeah. this region essentially, you know,
the eastern uh shore of the
Mediterranean Sea essentially. So the
Canonite people, they lived in this
region. We're talking about maybe 2,000
BC or something, maybe 1500 BC around
that time.
And near Jerusalem, there was uh where
is Jerusalem? Jerusalem is here. And
somewhere near Jerusalem, there was this
place where these Canonites practiced
this horrific set of rituals. And that
place was called Thet.
And later you have the Phoenician people
who who set up Carthage. Okay, Carthage
was based out of Tunis was it? I'm sure
it was Tunis. Let me find it if I can
without using the search feature in the
map. Am I able to find
Am I able to find this is not Carthage,
historical Carthage? Give me a second.
Here we have it. The archaeological site
of Carth Carthage. The Punic ports of
Carthage. You see this? This is the
ancient harbor of Carthage, the ancient
port of Carthage. And uh you have the
theater of Carthage, ancient
amphitheater of Carthage. And where is
the toet of Carthage? There we have it.
So this is the place where in Carthage
apparently the most horrific things
happened.
Okay, this is the Tophet.
Let's see if I can find some images.
Obviously, you won't find anything
ghastly here because it's very ancient
about 2 and a half thousand years ago.
So, this is where allegedly the the
Carthaginian people used to practice um
the offering of children to the god bal
means the lord in um in the the punic in
the in the canonite and Phoenician
languages. So what was found by
archaeologists in this region is tens of
thousands of urns
urns
uh
sacrificial urns that contained
uh the burnt remains of infants and
small animals. Okay. Uh that's what
archaeologists found
in the tophet
in Carthage.
And there are inscriptions talking about
offerings to the god Bal Hadad or Bal
Hamash or something. Bal something one
of the Bal gods, the Bal god of
Carthage, B A L. Bal.
So it looks like these were human
sacrifices, child sacrifices. And
typically the Greeks, no not the Greeks,
the Romans wrote about this that the
people of Carthage had this ghastly evil
uh tradition in which they they they
offered children to this metallic bronze
idol of some god and that god that idol
would be heated red hot and the children
would be burned on that that sort of
thing. And this entire practice seems to
have started in the out near Jerusalem
with the Canonites. The Canonites were
probably a Judeaic people,
right? And the Hebrew Bible speaks about
them and alleges that these people were
very evil and they practiced child
sacrifice.
So yeah, so that's the kind of dark
history we have and looks like this sort
of practice has continued behind the
scenes in western culture and that's
what we that's what apparently the rich
and powerful people of the US seem to be
still practicing apparently. You know
there are whispers and and allegations
about this.
So I don't know how true or false that
is but definitely we have this this
instance in history but you had the
canonites who practiced child sacrifice
burning of children um near Jerusalem
and eventually this practice spread to
North Africa present day Tunisia that
region in Carthage and the
archaeologists have found tens of
thousands of urns that contain such um
apparent child sacrifices. So that's the
deal. That's I think western culture.
Yeah. Now human sacrifice in Indian
culture.
Human sacrifice in Indian culture.
We obviously have you know certain gods
and goddesses that require human
sacrifice.
For example, goddess Da. She wears the
the necklace the mala of human heads.
You also have uh another goddess,
goddess Chamunda. If you see her Mortis,
you will see that she is this very scary
looking goddess who has a necklace of
human heads.
And uh the goddess Chamunda was the uh
kulvi of various Rajput families. She
still is the Kul Dvi of various Rajput
families.
And uh well
in the past when Indians still ruled
Indians, our king still ruled us that
time it was um required that sometimes
you should offer human sacrifices to a
goddess like Chamun. Now the question is
who would be chosen for sacrifice?
Is the Hindu religion a bloodthirsty
religion that requires human sacrifices?
Then you would choose people for human
sacrifice. No, it's not like that.
Goddess Chamunda was the Kula Dvi of
Rajputs because Rajputs were supposed to
fight the evil people right they were
supposed to fight off invaders and
whoever else sought to you know disrupt
our way of life and from about 700 AD
there was no death of such of such
monsters who sought to destroy India.
So who did he choose for human
sacrifice? the enemies of civilization,
the barbarians who sought to invade
India and plunder and destroy India.
That's who you sacrificed. Either you
sac, you know, you defeated them in
battle and brought the heads back and
gave it to the goddess or you took the
prisoners and brought them to the
goddess and then dealt with them in a
manner that pleased the goddess. That's
what you did. Children, absolutely
never. We are not a monstrous. I mean,
we are a civilization. We are the
greatest and oldest civilization.
There's no there's no you never hurt
children. That's not our culture. That's
Canonite culture. That's Phoenician
culture. That's American culture. That's
Jeffrey Epstein and US elite culture to
hurt children. You don't hurt children
in Indian culture. Never. Never.
So the coconuts were all were all adults
to and later on you know Indians became
very soft and stopped sacrificing
monsters stopped killing monsters and
then you would offer coconuts to
goddesses like Dura and Chamunda
that's where we went soft I suppose.
Okay, next question.
Okay, we're still dealing with Epstein.
Lagu online says epste files have
gathered more attention than any war
news in the entire social media in the
entire world social media in the past
few days. The most unsolved question is
what was Stephen Hawking doing there? I
mean how jokes apart I've learned that
never believe or trust biographies or
autobiographies of anyone or take them
just as a piece of entertainment not
even infotainment. Yeah. So Stephen
Hawking apparently is uh I think there
are pictures of him on Epstein Island
apparently and there's definitely
evidence in the Epstein files that
Stephen Hawking went to Epstein Island.
Where is Epstein Island by the way?
Okay, I didn't mention that.
So Epstein Island was this island. It is
this island. It's called Little St.
James or something. It's in the
Caribbean region. The West Indies
region. Okay, let's try and find it. Is
it in the Bahamas?
Uh, Little St. James Island. Let me see.
Little St. James Island.
Um, is it the US VI? Oh, Virgin Islands.
It's the US Virgin Islands. Okay. I was
not able to look at it's okay. Okay.
Okay. Okay. So, you zoom out. You have
San Huan. Okay. It's It's east of Puerto
Rico, US Virgin Islands
in the West Indies.
Okay. Um, and if you zoom in, you have
this little island here. And this is the
little St. James Island. And if you look
into that, you will find u Yeah.
Whatever. Yeah. The Epstein residence,
mansion,
and whatever else he had over there. So,
this is Epstein Island.
And, uh, apparently Dr. Stephen Hawking
visited this island. What was he doing
there? Well, one wonders.
Clearly, he was up to no good. And near
this island, okay, near the this little
Saint St. James Island, there is another
interesting island. Let me see. Is this
the one? What is this called? This is
Steven K. Not this one. Give me a
second. There's another rather
Interesting island over here.
Where is it? Where is it?
Not the great St. James Island. What is
this one? Dog Island. Dog rocks. Not
this one. Let me just search for it.
Okay.
Neker Island. Where is it?
This is Neker Island.
And uh
where exactly are we?
Okay, so little St. James is here.
Okay, and Neker Island
is all the way here. Who owns Neker
Island? It is Richard Branson who owns
Neker Island. This is another privately
owned island.
And uh yeah
uh anyhow that's that's about the
Epstein island and all of that. Now the
question we're talking about is about
Stephen Hawking. Professor Stephen
Hawking the man who proved that black
holes radiate. One of the great
scientists of the 20th century who died
in the 21st century. Um
and he was there. He visited Epstein
Island at least once probably. I don't
know at least once. We know that. What
was he doing that? How was he doing
that? uh given the fact that he was
completely paralyzed, I have no idea. Uh
but yeah, it's kind of um it changes
your entire perspective and perception
of a person. I mean, I come from a
physics background. I have used Hawkings
research in my own work in my own
research and I kind of looked up to him,
looked up to Stephen Hawking very much
and today my entire image that I had in
my mind of Stephen Hawking is kind of
shattered now.
Yeah. Many people would have idolized
Elon Musk. Many people would have
idolized Bill Gates
and whoever.
While those people they'll be shattered
today. They'll be heartbroken. I'm glad
Arnold Schwarzenegger doesn't figure in
that. Neither does SA Stallone as far as
I know. Even Charlie Sheen doesn't
figure in the Epstein files. Anyhow, so
I agree with Lero online that don't
believe these biographies,
autobiographies. They often are
commissioned to portrait various people
in a very good light and uh the truth
may be very different from what we
imagine. Right? So, so the point is
don't hero worship anybody.
Understand that all human beings there's
the possibility that they have ma major
flaws that are hiding behind the scenes.
So don't hero worship anybody. Don't
idolize anybody. If you admire somebody
you should ask yourself what is it that
I admire about this person? What
qualities do I admire? Admire qualities
don't admire people. That that that is a
more grounded way of of admiring people
I suppose.
Okay. Now let's move on to something
beyond Epstein. We've spent 40 minutes
on Epstein, right? Okay. Let's move on.
Okay. Now we have too many questions
here, do we? Okay. You got a bunch of
questions here about the US India trade
deal. Okay, let's begin. Amisha says US
India trade deal seems like an order
dictated to India by the USA. Why is the
Indian government not forthcoming on the
details agreed upon in this trade deal?
Modi has not mentioned anything apart
from tariff reduction. No use of the
specific word trade deal. No mention of
$500 billion investment or reduction of
Russian oil. Is Trump again exaggerating
all these things? Real Puddin says many
people are saying that India is
compromised with the recent trade deal
of the US but India being a weaker
nation has to agree on some compromises
given that we are retaining our
sovereignty. Sam says is it a good move
by Bhat to do a trade deal with the US
at this point in time where the US is
openly behaving like an imperial power.
Recently the US abandoned their trade
deal with South Korea and increase the
tariffs on South Korea. So what do you
think it's going to be? Is it beneficial
for Barat? Mriangaswaris says, "What's
your assessment of the India US trade
deal given India's repeated reported
commitments to reduce reduce Russian oil
purchases by US and Venezuelan crude and
agree to purchase US agricultural
produce and yet secure lower tariffs
than all regional peers? Do you see this
as a calculated trade-off or early signs
of economic vasilization under US
pressure?" Rushab says, "What's
happening between India and Venezuela?"
PM Modi called Deli Rodriguez. Now the U
recent India US trade deal has happened
even if we don't consider Donald Trump's
claims of India stopping Russian oil. It
is clear that India is looking towards
other options which even Russian foreign
ministry spokeswoman acknowledged and it
is also true that Reliance had the
waiver to buy oil till Donald J. Trump
scrabbed it. We have one of the largest
refining capability capacities in the
world. So is Venezuelan oil feasible for
India economically? Amisha says $500
billion deal, no Russian oil, 18%
tariffs. How will $500 billion deal be
achieved? How is that a fair deal? Does
did India open its agricultural sector
that has long been an issue for not
getting the trade deal in the first
place? All these questions. There is
more. There is more.
And now we have these questions.
Abhishek Shukla live says your views on
the India US trade deal on the surface I
think India lost in US won.
Agnivan says your views on the recent
India US trade deal. Is India now an
American vasal? Soldier boy says well
about the recent trade deal with the USA
are we doomed? Have we given up? Are we
vasalized? What is next? Aayush says
please share your detailed analysis of
this recent India US trade deal. Nan
Joti Bora says, "Is the newly announced
trade deal with the US the last nail in
the coffin for our sovereignty?" So much
concern everybody has. So much concern
everyone has. Why is everybody so
concerned
is the question.
Why is everyone so concerned? Because
you have
Indian politicians celebrating the trade
deal. You have Indian politicians
felicitating the prime minister for the
trade deal.
Everyone's announcing that the trade
deals are some fantastic thing
especially um in parliament and what not
and the opposition politicians are
saying it's a terrible deal and so on
right and that's why everyone is so
concerned but what is the truth what's
happened
so let's let's look at what's happened
first of all based on um the
pronouncements of various politicians so
first of all we have this okay this is a
tweet from the white
It was on February 2. Today is February
6. Sir, what does this say? It's a
readout of what Donald J. Trump said. It
was an honor to speak with Prime
Minister Modi of India this morning. He
is one of my greatest friends and a
powerful and respected leader of his
country. We spoke about many things
including trade and ending the war with
Russia and Ukraine. He agreed to stop
buying Russian oil and to buy much more
from the United States and potentially
Venezuela. This will help end the war in
Ukraine which is place taking place
right now with thousands of people dying
each and every week out of friendship
and respect for Prime Minister Modi and
as per his request effective
immediately. We agreed to a trade deal
between the United States and India
whereby the United States will charge a
reduced reciprocal tariff lowering it
from 25% to 18%. They will likewise move
forward to reduce their tariffs and
non-tariff barriers against the United
States to capital zero. The prime
minister also committed to buy American
at a much higher level in addition to
over $500 billion of US energy,
technology, agricultural, coal and many
other products. Our amazing relationship
with India will be even stronger going
forward. Prime Minister Modi and I are
two people that get things done.
Something that cannot be said for most.
Thank you for your attention to this
matter. Okay. So that is what Trump has
uh tweeted. Now what has been the
response of the Indian prime minister?
What's been the response? Let's find
out.
Mr. Modi tweeted this as soon as he
could. Wonderful to speak with my dear
friend President Trump today. Delighted
that made making made in India products
will now have a reduced tariff of 18%.
Big thanks to President Trump on behalf
of the 1.4 billion people of India for
this wonderful announcement. When two
large economies and the world's largest
democracies work together, it benefits
our people and unlocks immense potential
opportunities for mutually beneficial
cooperation. President Trump's
leadership is vital for global peace,
stability, and prosperity. India fully
supports his efforts for peace. I look
forward to working closely with him to
take our partnership to unprecedented
heights. That that's what the prime
minister of India uh tweeted on on on on
X. Now, so what's the deal?
Is this a disaster for India. My
friends, here's the truth. There is no
India US trade deal.
This is the truth. As of today, 6th of
February, 2026, there is no India US
trade deal. Nothing has been signed.
Nothing has been signed. No trade deal
has been signed. But Trump has gone
ahead and tweeted this thing out. Once
again, let's put this on the screen. He
has gone ahead and tweeted this out.
What Trump has done, you know what it's
called? It's called gaslighting.
India has not agreed to even half of
these things. Right now, the
negotiations are still going on.
But Trump has tweeted as if this is done
as if the trade deal has been signed.
That's how he has tweeted and he has
already decided what is India is going
to do that but India is going to stop
buying Russian oil and India is going to
bring the tariffs on the US goods
products down to zero and the US will
only apply then 18% tariffs so India
will have zero tariffs on US goods but
the US will have 18% tariffs on Indian
goods super unequal super unequal right
and he says that India will stop buying
Russian oil India will potentially buy
much more oil from Venezuela India will
buy US agricultural products
and so many more things. India will
purchase $500 billion of god knows what
other things. Trump has already decided
all these things on behalf of India.
India has not agreed to any of this. If
it was agreed, it would have been
signed. No such signing ceremony or any
such thing has happened. The
negotiations are still on.
So
here's the answer to your question. If
what Trump has announced, if India
accepts all of that,
then the US wins, India loses. What
Trump is saying is that the US will
impose only 18% tariffs on Indian goods
and India will impose 0% tariffs on
American goods. That is a master slave
relationship. That is an East India
Company versus India relationship. If we
agree to what Trump says, that is
unacceptable to India. At least if I was
in charge, I would reject this
agricultural products. If we start
importing American agricultural
products, it will destroy our farm
economy. It'll destroy the Indian
agricultural sector. How can the in
government agree to that? That's again
something we can't agree to.
And if you when I have tariffs, tariffs
have to be reciprocal. So if you are
imposing 18%, I will impose 18%.
If you are powerful, okay, you impose
18, I'll impose 10. But it can't be 18
and zero. So the terms that he has
announced are once again maximalist
terms. Why has the India US trade deal
not happened all after all these months
of negotiations? Because the Americans
are adopting a maximalist position. They
are saying we take everything you get
nothing.
That's exactly what Trump has tweeted
out. If India accepts what Trump has
tweeted out, you can say that we are of
American basal.
If India accepts what he has tweeted
out, India loses, the US wins, India
starts walking down the road of
vasalhood, American vasalhood. If we
accept what Trump has tweeted, then we
are doomed. We are vasalized.
Right?
That will be the first not the last nail
but the first nail in the coffin of our
sovereignty.
So the point is no trade deal has
happened. That's the first and foremost
thing we have to keep in mind. Nothing
has been signed.
Trump is gaslighting the world. He's
gaslighting India. He's applying
pressure on India. He's bullying India
by tweeting such things out. And when
you see Modi's tweet, you will not see
any of that. You will not see Modi
saying in this tweet that we will stop
buying Russian oil. You will not see
Modi saying that we will buy $500
billion of what not. He's You'll not see
Modi saying that we will open up our
agricultural sector to the Americans and
so on. Modi has said none of those
things. He has simply said thank you Mr.
Trump blah blah blah blah blah because
when Trump says something, we have to
say something nice to him. Okay? You to
keep him happy. You have to be very
polite and very differential to him. So
that's what Mr. Modi has done. He has
not agreed or accepted.
He has not agreed to any of the terms
that Trump has put out. He has not Mr.
Modi has not accepted any of any of
those terms.
So what is the status of the India US
trade deal? The status is there is no
trade deal as of today.
The Americans are still adopting a
maximalist position.
Will a trade deal happen soon? It may
happen soon depending on whether the US
is willing to be a little reasonable
or not. If the US continues with its
maximalist position, I would say India
should not sign anything. And that's the
situation. So India has not lost. The US
has not won. India has not become a US
wasal. The nails in the coffin of our
sovereignty have not been hammered in
yet. Okay. uh Venezuela. Yeah, looks
like India will buy some Venezuelan oil,
but the Venezuelans don't have much of a
capability to let's say replace the
Russian oil that we are getting. So, it
won't make much of a difference. So, end
of the day, the bottom line is this.
There is as of today,
6th of February 2026, there is as of
today no trade deal between India and
the US. Nothing.
Amisha says, "Will India lose Russia as
an ally if India doesn't buy Russian
oil? It feels like we're going to lose
Russia as an ally, at least to me." I
would like to hear your thoughts on
opinions on this. Rohan says, "Your
views on India allowed to buy oil from
Venezuela. India will get uh cheap oil
from Venezuela and particularly high
from USA. So it will cost as much as
Russian oil. What are your overview
overall views on India US trade?" Okay,
I discussed the trade deal which is no
trade deal. But here is an interesting
uh tweet from uh Prime Minister Modi of
India.
So this was uh on January 30, 2026.
Okay, today is February 6, 2026. Mr.
Modi said says spoke with acting
president of Venezuela, Miss Deli
Rodriguez. We agreed to further deepen
and expand our bilateral partnership in
all areas with a shared vision of taking
India Venezuela relations to new heights
in the years ahead. So that's what Mr.
Modi has tweeted he has not said
anything about oil but clearly Venezuela
its its relevance to the world today is
that of its oil right that's what the US
has reduced Venezuela to to a nation
that is synonymous with oil
so maybe the Americans insisted that
India the prime minister of India should
speak with his Venezuelan acting
counterpart the acting leader of
Venezuela and maybe discuss oil
purchases potential oil purchases or
whatever and then Trump has gone ahead
and said that you know India may be
purchasing large quantities of
Venezuelan oil. Now the thing is
Venezuela does have about possibly about
20% of the world's proven oil reserves
but it's capacity of exporting oil
extracting and exporting oil is is is
just a fraction of the oil reserves.
uh it India imports a very large
quantity of u okay let's let's find out
okay let's find out in real time how
much
how many barrels of okay let's let's uh
ask Google's AI about this how many
barrels
of Russian
oil
did India import
um in J in
Jan and 26 let's see
in January 1.16 million to okay let's
say 1.2 billion million barrels per day
that's what India imported okay so keep
this in mind put make a note of this
every day India was importing 1.2 2
million barrels of Russian oil, Russian
crude oil. Okay. Uh, how many barrels of
of of
crude can venezuela
produce per day? How many barrels of
oil? 800,000. Not even 1 million barrels
of oil per day. So, Venezuela's oil
production is currently 800,000
barrels per day. India is importing 1.2
million barrels per day from Russia. Can
Venezuela replace that even if it sends
all of its oil to India? No. No. No. No.
No. Not possible.
Venezuela can't replace that. Secondly,
the Venezuelan oil is a different grade
compared to the Russian oil. Venezuela's
oil is extra heavy sour crude oil. It's
very thick and it's got very high sulfur
content. Only four refineries in the
world can process that oil. One of those
refineries is in India.
But uh it's not suitable for everything.
It's suitable for maybe producing
asphalt, maybe producing diesel, but
what about petrol and other things? Very
hard to extract that from Venezuelan
crude. But the Russian crude which is
also heavy but not that sour and not
that heavy we can extract other you know
petrol etc from that. So we can't
replace Russian crude with Venezuelan
crude. It doesn't work. Makes no sense.
Right
now the thing is the Americans have now
allowed magnanimously India to purchase
Venezuelan oil. Until 2010
about 10% of India's oil imports came
from Venezuela. Then the Americans came
and said India can no longer purchase
Russ Venezuelan crude oil. We forbid it.
So India obediently stopped buying
Venezuelan crude oil. Now the Americans
have magnanimously allowed us given us
permission. Okay, now you can buy again.
But it's not like we we're going to take
their orders all the time. And secondly,
Venezuelan crude oil is not suitable for
all our requirements and it's not
sufficient for our requirements.
And lastly, our relationship with Russia
is very important. Russia is a nation
that we can trust way more than the US.
It is the nation we can trust the most
among all the nations we deal with. We
have a very long-standing tried and
tested relationship with Russia. We've
had some ups and downs. We've had some
irritants. Any relationship with any two
nations is going to have some irritants.
But overall, Russia has never done
something anything that has
harmed India's national interests to any
significant level and neither has India
done the same to Russia. So we can trust
Russia. Russia doesn't supply Russia
doesn't fund and finance Pakistani
terrorism against us. The Americans did
that with Pakistan from the 1980s
onwards. Russia has never done that. You
can't trust the Americans to the extent
we can trust the Russians. And we don't
want Russia to become completely
dependent on China if we stop purchasing
Russian crude oil. Russia, it would be a
big setback to Russia.
We need Russia to to be strong. We need
Russia to be relevant. We can't allow
Russia to become a Chinese vasal.
It is India that prevented Russia from
sliding into Chinese vasal load from
2022 onwards because we started
purchasing large quantities of Russian
oil and that acted as a pressure release
valve for Russia. Otherwise it would
have been become completely isolated in
the world and completely dependent on
China. We prevented that from happening
and we have to keep playing that role.
So I don't think India will ever
stop purchasing Russian oil. It's not
about prices.
It's not only about prices. Okay, prices
matter and that's why Russia will ensure
that it doesn't sell India overpriced
oil. the oil the Russians sell to us are
it's typically slightly lower than the
market rate you know going market rate
so they are also honoring
u the relationship right they're also
respecting the fact that we are helping
them out
so I think that relationship will
continue I don't think we will stop uh
purchasing Russian oil if we do stop
purchasing Russian oil it is a very big
red flag of Indian vasaro to the US in
my opinion okay it's going to be a very
big red flag for
that India is now on the way on the road
towards becoming a US vasal if we stop
purchasing Russian oil. What do we get
in exchange? What Venezuelan oil? A pat
on the back from Uncle Trump. We don't
need that. Okay. So, yeah.
Saratanic says, "What is the future of
Iran? US is constantly increasing its
firepower in West Asia just like what
they did in Venezuela before abducting
Nicolas Maduro. What action can the US
take against Iran?" According to me,
Rush T says, "US and Iran have nuclear
talks in Oman. Iran seems to tone down
their narrative. The US looks the US too
looks aligned for a deal, but they still
maintain their naval Armada in the
Middle East. Uh they've ordered the US
citizens to leave Iran. What's next?
Will there be no war or is there still a
chance of war? How do you see it from
the Israeli and Indian perspective?
Okay.
The future of Iran. So, right now the
Americans have built up a massive naval
presence, a reasonably large naval
presence in um the western Indian Ocean,
the so-called Arabian Sea. Let's find
out where. Okay, for illustrative
purposes, I'm going to give you the
general area where this is happening.
It's not necessarily the exact location
of the American warships, but close
enough. So, we're talking about the
so-called Arabian Sea. That's the
western Indian Ocean, the Gulf of Oman
region near that, not too close to the
Iran uh Iran coast, but definitely the
western Indian Ocean region and you will
have a presence of US ships in this
region, maybe even the Red Sea, but
mainly the western Indian Ocean and of
course the US has this place called Vie
Garcia from where they can project
massive power in the subcontinent and
extended subcontinent region in which we
also have Iran. So the Americans can u
have you know strategic bombers long
distance bombers take off from here.
They can also have aircraft carriers
that are stationed here and that's the
artha.
So the Americans have built up a massive
reasonably strong and increasing uh
naval presence in this region. So what's
going to happen? Are the so are the
Americans going to going to invade Iran
Iran
or are they simply using this naval
presence as
as a tool to arm twist Iran to get the
Iranians to do what the Americans want?
So let's ask ourselves what do the
Americans want with Iran? The Americans
want essentially two things. They want
Iran to dismantle its nuclear program.
That's number one. Number two, they want
control over Iran's oil. The Americans
don't care about whether it's an Islamic
regime or a Zoroastrian regime or an
atheistic regime or a Christian regime
in Iran. They only care about the oil.
They'll be very happy to to to work with
the current government of Iran as long
as this government accepts American
conditions of uh allowing the Americans
to decide the fate of Iranian oil. Sell
all the oil to America or to nations
America allows you to sell to. Don't
sell to China. The objective is to
squeeze China. And of course, the
Iranians must dismantle their nuclear,
roll back their nuclear program
verifiably. These are the two things the
Americans want. They are not really
interested in a regime change per se. Uh
that's also what Israel wants as long as
the Iranians demonstrabably dismantle
the nuclear program and um that's number
one that Israel wants, but Israel will
not be satisfied with that. Israel also
knows that the Iranians have god knows
how many missiles of various kinds which
can do tremendous damage to Israel and
that can circumvent the Iron Dome that
the Israelis have. So, Israel actually
wants a regime change in Thran. Israel
will not be satisfied with mere control
over Iranian oil and the roll back of
the nuclear program. Israel wants a
regime change. The US is okay with just
the roll back of the nuclear program and
control of oil of Iran oil Iranian oil.
From the Indian perspective, what do we
seek? We would like the Iranian
government to stay in place.
Okay. Geopolitically, we need this
government to stay in place, the current
government. If there is a regime change
in Iran and the so-called democratic
government comes to power or or if the
Americans parachute Razapheli to power
then Iran becomes a super Pakistan for
us a pro-American nation a US vasal much
larger much more powerful than Pakistan
and it will be proakistan in that case
if Iran falls to the Americans in regime
change then in a year or two you may
have American troops in Pakistan
occupied Kashmir so a Regime change in
Iran is not in India's favor. India
doesn't want that. From our perspective,
we don't need that. We don't want that.
From Israel's perspective, regime change
is what they want. From America's
perspective, um they want a roll back of
the nuclear program and control of the
Iranian oil. What will Iran do about
this? Iran is under tremendous pressure.
Iran has a lot of firepower, missile
firepower, but u the Americans can still
defeat Iran, okay, at at a very high
cost. But it's possible. So if the
Americans launch a military invasion, it
will be very costly, very damaging, and
it'll take a lot of time, energy,
effort, dollars, but the Americans will
eventually win. But do the Americans
want to take all the trouble of a of a
military invasion? The other option the
Americans have is is is proxy war
against Iran. Like in the 1980s, 1990s,
2010s, the Americans funded and financed
Pakistani terrorism against India,
bleeding India by a thousand cuts. The
Americans could do the same to Iran.
They could use Pakistani terrorists on
Iran's eastern border to infiltrate Iran
and bleed Iran. Pakistan is is the
world's biggest uh expert in terrorism.
It's the epicenter of terrorism, right?
And on the western front of Iran's
western border, the Americans could use
ISIS and al-Qaeda
to bleed Iran to infiltrate and bleed
Iran. So one of the American vasal
states in West Asia is Syria. Syria was
ruled by Bashar al-Assad. Now he has
he's in Moscow apparently and Syria is
now ruled by a terrorist ISIS terrorist
called Julani.
His known was Julani. Julani now he's
called al-Shara or whatever. So he's an
ISIS terrorist. He is an American ally.
He controls a bunch of ISIS fighters.
Turkey is handin glove with ISIS. So
Turkey and the Julani fellow they could
infiltrate Iran in various ways with
ISIS fighters and do terrible things. So
by that doing that you can destabilize
Iran over time and perhaps do regime
change. There is these are various
options the Americans have. Maybe a
hybrid approach or whatever. So what's
the future of Iran? The future of Iran
is shaky. Iran has tremendous enemies in
the region. Um obviously there are
countries in the region who don't want a
military invasion of Iran because that
will be very destabilizing for the
region. So maybe the Americans will go
for the other other option of using
terrorism and uh Pakistani and ISIS
terrorism and al-Qaeda terrorism against
Iran. That's a possibility. So we're
going to have nuclear talks in Iran.
What's going to happen? They'll they'll
fail. Iran will refuse to dismantle its
nuclear program most likely. If they
agree then the next demand will be much
higher. You guys resign and leave. So I
don't see that happening.
So yeah that's that's where India that's
where Iran is today in a very precarious
situation but still powerful still
strong to powerful enough to to
significantly withstand
an US attempt to invade it.
Rushup Tar says, "What is happening in
the ties between India and the Middle
East? On the one side, our deputy NSA,
National Security Adviser goes to Iran
and meets with Iranian officials. Uh,
chief of defense services staff Anil
Johan went to Armenia, met uh PM
Pashinan of Armenia and paid tribute to
1.5 million Armenians who were killed by
the Turks in the Armenian genocide. Uh,
India's NSA Ajit Dwal is in Saudi
Arabia. India and the Gulf cooperation
council sign FDA reference terms in
presence of P goel India UAE and India
Israel ties remain at all-time highs.
What exactly is India's strategy in the
Middle East? Okay,
let's understand what's happening in the
Middle East. There is an unseen rivalry
that has now come to light in the Middle
East and this rivalry is Saudi Arabia
versus UAE.
See, UAE from the 1970s, 1980 onwards
has been focused on development. It has
been laser focused on becoming an
attractive destination for expatriots to
live in, an attractive destination for
foreign direct investment, an attractive
invest destination uh for tourism and so
many other things. And the UAE has
worked really really hard to to make
this happen. And today the UAE is a big
success story. About 40% of UAE's
population is of Indian origin. They are
not citizens. They are long-term
residents or short-term residents. But
40% of the population is Indian origin.
A lot of people from the west live in uh
the UAE. U the UAE is super successful,
super wealthy. Um Abu Dhabi has a lot of
oil. Dubai has a lot of expats and um
you have Hindu temples there and
whatnot. Right. So it's a success story.
It's a great success story. the UAE
they've worked very hard for this and
they deserve the success that they have
achieved.
Now Saudi Arabia tried to do that.
Um there was this uh upheaval in Saudi
Arabia in the 2010s late 2010s and
Prince Muhammad bin Salman became the de
facto ruler of Saudi Arabia and he tried
to copy the UAE
trajectory. So he uh liberalized Saudi
society. He gave uh Saudi ladies, Saudi
women the right to come out in public
without coverings I suppose and drive
automobiles and all that and he embarked
on these massive infrastructure projects
like the the like the Lion City and
Neome and whatnot but it's not really
worked out
because in the in the UAE the quality of
the population is very high. They're
very well educated and they they are you
know more liberal, more western, more
secular. whatever you want to call them,
right? Highly educated.
The Saudi population is very different.
So, it's not really that's one one of
various factors. Okay? So, Saudi Arabia
tried to become a super UAE kind of
country. It has not worked out. And now
Saudi Arabia has decided that we're
going to revert to what we really are.
So, Saudi Arabia last year um signed
this deal with Pakistan, mutual defense
deal. If somebody attacks Saudi Arabia,
Pakistan will come to Saudi Arabia's
rescue. If somebody attacks Pakistan,
Saudi Arabia will come to Pakistan's
rescue. That sort of thing which is very
anti-India obviously. And Saudi Arabia
and Pakistan have another partner which
is Turkey.
Okay, which is like a western Asian
version of Pakistan, a slightly lighter
skinned version of Pakistan. But once
again, Turkey is a nation that doesn't
have a history. It has a criminal
record. Armenian genocide, right? the
Ottoman Empire and the horrific
brutalities it did. So their history is
more of a criminal record than a history
and their approach they are handin-
glove with ISIS the Turks. So once again
just like Pakistan very terroristic
tendencies. So Saudi Arabia Pakistan and
Turkey are now this alliance you could
say in West Asia. Pakistan obviously in
the in in the subcontinent and Saudi
Arabia and and Turkey are in West Asia.
Now there's a Saudi Arabia versus UAE
rivalry also and I'll not go into the
details of that otherwise it becomes too
long but these two nations are rivals
Saudi Arabia and UAE they are rivals in
Yemen they are rivals in the Horn of
Africa in Sudan in Somalia everywhere in
Somali land also and so on and so forth.
Uh so there's this rivalry Saudi Arabia
versus UAE. Now
the UAE and India have an excellent
relationship excellent relationship.
Okay. One of the very visible reasons is
that we 40% roughly of UA's population
of is of Indian origin. There are Hindu
temples in the UAE. India and the UAE
have a very robust you know we have an
FDA. We have defense relations. It's
it's a great relationship. Okay. And
there's another partner in this India UA
relationship which is Israel. UAE and
Israel also are also on very good terms
and India and Israel are obviously on
excellent terms. So it's India, UAE,
Israel versus Saudi Arabia, Pakistan,
Turkey. That is the situation in uh in
West Asia. When it comes to Armenia,
India and Israel are kind of on opposite
sides because India supports Armenia but
Israel supports Azarbaijan. But Israel
doesn't support support Azarbaijan out
of ideological reasons. It supports
Azarbaijan because it seeks Azarbaijani
oil. Israel needs that, right? It gets
oil and hydrocarbons from Azarbaijan and
Azarbaijan and Turkey seek to erase
Armenia from the map of the world and
India and Iran are working together to
prevent this from happening and to to
support Armenia. So that is the
situation. We also have a very good
relationship with Greece which is kind
of west of Turkey. Turkey squats on
Greek territory obviously Anatolia which
is a whole different story and Turkey is
a dggressor towards Greece and towards
Cyprus and India has good relations with
with Greece and Cypress so there's a
whole lot happening in this region and
that essentially is India's situation
India strategy in the Middle East
Gorav Pagar says if Japan is said to be
acquiring nukes in a few years wouldn't
that then pave the path for Japan to get
to gain a bit of sovereign
So, uh, when did Henry Kissinger
tragically pass away? Let me just see. I
think it was, uh, like 23 was it?
Henry
Kissinger. When did he die? He
tragically passed away in November 2023
at the age of 99. Very tragic. Now, um,
Mr. Kissinger a few months before he
passed away, tragically, he said that
Japan will most likely become a nuclear
power in the next 5 years. So we have a
deadline of 2028 to see whether Mr.
Kissinger was correct or not in his
assessment. He typically used to be
correct in whatever he said. He had very
good understanding of the world. So
let's say Japan becomes a nuclear power
in by 2028. Does that mean that they
will acquire some sovereignty because of
the nukes?
Ask yourselves this question. The UK has
nukes. Is the UK a sovereign nation? The
UK is not a sovereign nation.
The UK is a hard and fast vassal of the
US. Why is the UK a vasal of the US?
Because the
UK's nuclear warheads
are are mated to American missiles. So
let's say this is the the British
warhead.
The British made the warhead, but the
missile is American. So who who has the
big red button? Is it uh whoever is the
prime minister of the UK? No, the big
red button isn't in London, it's in
Washington. So despite the UK having
nukes on paper,
the actual control of the nukes is in
Washington. Similarly, if the Americans
allow Japan to acquire nukes,
do you think the Americans will allow
the Japanese to actually manufacture the
nukes? No. They will transfer some
American nukes to Japanese soil and
those nukes will be 100% entirely
controlled by American troops. There are
more than 130 permanent US military
bases on Japanese territory. Those nukes
will be stationed in one of in some of
these bases. They'll be controlled
entirely by the US, but on paper they
will be Japanese nukes.
Does this look like a sovereignty
arrangement for you? Pakistan has nukes,
right? Apparently. Do you think those
are Pakistani nukes? I am certain
obviously without evidence but I'm
certain these are American nukes on
Pakistani soil and the objective is to
threaten India. So it's not like the
Pakistanis have any control over those
nukes. The Americans control those
nukes. See what happened in operation.
What happened to Pakistan's nuclear
blackmail and bluff? What happened? We
hammered them. What did the Pakistanis
do? They ran to the Americans pleading
for mercy.
So the point is if Japan acquires nukes
those nukes will be on Japanese
territory on paper. No actually they'll
be on Japanese territory but they will
belong to Japan only on paper only
technically they will actually be owned
and operated and 100% controlled by
American generals and American troops.
So no sovereignty unfortunately.
Okay. Okay. Three questions here. Arya
Vashisha says when will we see Banglad
the first Bangladeshi deputy prime
minister of India as Manipur now has one
cookie deputy chief minister we can't
protect our land and our citizens real
the BJP government of Manipur has has
installed Ncha keep gin who is a cookie
as deputy chief minister of Manipur are
we infiltrated Vashishtra says I don't
know whether you will take this question
or not but seeing a cookie become deputy
chief minister of manipur boils my blood
what the hell we can't we can't protect
our land our citizens to make things
even worse we are collo collaborating
with the infiltrators to help with
democracy human rights to help with this
constitution the system a lot of
frustration so u it looks like manipur
now has uh the president's rule has
ended apparently in Manipur and there's
new chief minister of manipur u and two
deputy chief ministers so the chief
minister of manipur who is let's find
out who these people are okay let's
let's find out who the chief minister
deputy chief minister etc are um let's
ask a Google uh who is the new chief
minister who
who is the new CM of Manipur Manipur
it is uh Yumnam Kimchan Singh of the BJP
so Yumnam Kimchan Singh is a mate he
belongs to the indigenous uh community
of Manipur which is the mate community
okay they are the indigenous people of
Manipur the other indigenous people of
Manipur are the Nagas so who are the who
are the
new
deputy cms of Manipur.
So Nimcha Kipkin and Luci do uh Lucy do
is a naga person
and Nimcha Kipkin is uh a cookie person.
So let's find out about Nimcha Kipkin.
Who
is Nimcha Kipkin?
Uh is an Indian politician and Indian
politician member of the BJP serving as
deputy chief minister of Manipur since
2026.
A member of the Manipur legislative
assembly from Okay. Who it's a lady
right? Who is Nanka Kipkin?
Who is her husband
and what does he do?
So
let's find out
key details etc etc. Who's the husband?
Nimcha Kipgen is married to St. Tang Boy
Kipgen of occupation. Stangboy Kipgen is
the chairman of the Kuki National Front
Front.
The Kuki National Front is a militant
group
that has been under a SO agreement with
the government of India since 2028 2008.
So the husband of this person Nimcha
Kipkin is the chairman of the cookie
national front. Is Kookiland a nation?
Is Kookiland a nation? I wonder
if somebody calls Cookieand a nation or
a cookie nation, they're talking about
cookie land for Christ, right? So the
husband of this lady is the chairman of
the cookie national front. The KNF is a
militant group,
a militant group that has been in in in
this suspension of operations SO
agreement with the government of India
since 2008.
Now what can I say about this?
The deputy chief minister of Manipur is
a cookie person whose husband is the
chairman of the cookie national front a
militant group. I did not make the
claim. Google is showing us this. You
can do your own due diligence. You can
do your own factchecking.
This is the new government of Manipur.
Uh what can I say? Congratulations to
the people of Manipur and the people of
India. Great job government of India.
Great job. I have nothing more to say
about that.
Okay.
Billy Bob says, "As a British person who
has some Indian heritage, I would like
to know if you had the power to alter
the country, what changes would you make
to India to turn it into a global
superpower? From your previous videos,
India had a massive global economy until
economic predation by the British
Empire. How would you reverse this? And
is it even possible? It is possible. It
will take some time. What steps would I
take to to change the trajectory of the
country? I would first of all I would
say I would I would make it mandatory
for Indians to not utter the word
superpower or vishwaguru for at least 20
years. First thing no Indians no Indian
should be allowed to utter the words
superpower or vishwaguru for 20 years.
That's the first thing. The second thing
is I would eject all illegal
infiltrators who are squatting on Indian
territory. Whether they are Rohingya,
whether they are Bangladeshies, whether
they are cookies, whether they are
Pakistanis, whether they are whatever,
if they have come into India illegally,
they have to be expelled. That's that's
that has to happen at the earliest.
That's another thing I would do. The
third thing I would do
is reform the education system. 20 years
is a reasonable amount of time to reform
the education system. And what reforms?
I have made entire videos about that.
what reforms are needed in India. So I
would reform the education system. Um
next I would try my best to end
corruption the alleged corruption that
allegedly runs the entire system uh of
the country. That's another thing I
would do. And u
what else would I do? So education
system I would um education system I
would place special emphasis on Indian
culture or revival of Indian culture,
revival of Indian archaeological
heritage. um you know setting up
institutions that promote Indian in
culture and so on which the government
of India historically has never bothered
to do since 1947 until today. Uh I would
promote Indian tourism.
India has the potential to be the
superpower of tourism in the world but
uh doesn't give a damn. Right? So that's
another thing I would do and obviously I
would boast of the Indian military. I
would really really focus on indigenous
development of of various weapon systems
of aircraft of submarines of of ships um
of all kinds of things you know rifles
carbines
missiles all of that indigenize
everything as far as possible whatever
technology we're lacking buy borrow
steel whatever you need to do do that
focus on science in technology on AI on
quantum computing on space
research and exploration space well
settle settling in space all of that
these are some of the things I would do
is it possible it is possible it'll take
time but it won't happen under this
system the current system the the the
Westminster parliamentary democracy
system that we have and this federal
system where states have so many power
it just doesn't work for India
uh as long as India has the system India
well forget about superpower India won't
be even become a middle power right it's
just designed to fail it's It's it sets
India up for failure. It's it's it's it
guarantees mediocrity.
So the system has to be totally
reversed, totally totally reformed or
rather replaced. So what would I do? I
would do away with the constitution. I
would bring in at least a presidential
form of government. Well, ideally a
single president for 20 years. These are
some of the things that are needed.
Otherwise, India is destined for
mediocrity. The way we are going right
now, whoever the leaders are, it's India
is destined to remain mediocre the way
things are going. So it needs major
changes for sure.
Okay, let's talk about history now for a
bit. Amisha says what? Now Amisha says
where were the Vic texts composed
geographically? So we have four Vedas
and we will not discuss all four Vedas,
right? But uh let us talk about the
rigida. The oldest of the Vedas, the
oldest literature known to humankind. A
lot of people dispute that but it is the
oldest literature known to humankind.
The rigida. So what is the geography of
the rigida right? Uh the rigida has a
lot of geographical information. It has
a lot of climate information. It has
information about flora and fauna, about
trees, about uh grasses, about animals
and birds, about rivers, about
mountains, right? So all of this textual
literary information
helps you to place the the the the
geography of the of the rigida. Where
was the rigida composed? Right? So from
what we see
so for for example let's talk about
rivers okay the rigida mentions a lot of
rivers what are the rivers first of all
um so what is the river horizon of the
rigida it runs from Gandhar
Gandhar means Afghanistan the Kuba
region Kabul region okay north and west
it's the Gandhar region and south and
east It's the Kurukhetra region which is
Hana and the Ganga basin, the Ganga
Valley region in the east. Okay. And the
densest cluster essentially is the
Saptasindu region, the Sindu, the
Saraswati and essentially the seven
tributary rivers in the region. The
Saptasindu region which are these these
rivers. We obviously have the Saraswati,
the greatest of the rivers. We have the
Synindhu. We have the Vitashta which is
the Jalum river. We have the Akshi which
is which is the Chinab. We have the
Parni, the Ravi and the Vipasha river,
the Satlage, right? And we also have
various other rivers like the uh
Dishadwati.
Uh it also mentions the Yamuna. It also
obviously mentions the Ganga. So all of
these rivers tell us the geographical
region that the people of who wrote the
Rigida were aware of the the region they
lived in. So from Gandhara all the way
in the north and west to the Ganga
Valley region in the east, the south and
the east and the major focus is the
Saptasindu region and the major rivers
are the Saraspati and the Sindu in that
region. Okay. So the STAindu region is
essentially between the two great
rivers, the Saraspati and the Sindu. uh
the sundu is in the western part of the
sapas synindu and the saraspati is in
the eastern part of the saras of the um
sapasindu region and that obviously is
today's gagar hakra river okay so that
um so it's all the way from Afghanistan
to the punjab hana and western up region
and the focus is on Punjab clearly
there's no central Asia or far eastern
India or southern India in this okay
there's no central Asia all all of that
it is northern and western India what
kind of climate do we have? What kind of
landscape do we have? So the rigidic
hymns they repeatedly describe strong
monsoon. Okay, torrential rains in the
monsoon. And these torrential rains give
rise to this great river, the mother of
floods, the Sarasatwati. And the other
rivers are also swollen river, swollen
rivers, the swell in the monsoon and
storms and the breaking of drought by
these monsoon storms. Okay. So this is
clearly the signature of the Indian
rainy season climate, the monsoon
climate. This is nothing to do with
central Asia and the in the step region
of central Asia. Okay. And there are
mentions of arid conditions and
semi-arid conditions and the need for
wells and watering points. So that is
essentially talking about Rajasthan, the
Rajasthan area, the fringes of Rajasthan
on the margins of the monsoon uh region
of India. And obviously u the rigid
mentions the Himalayas the great
Himalayas to the north right. So if you
look at all of this evidence it's it's
consistent with the population living
south of the Himalayan range and within
the confines of the of the rivers that
we just discussed the the Sautasu region
mainly and west of the Ganga. I mean it
includes the Ganga plains west of that
and probably north of the present day
Rajasthan region but including the
northern fringes of the Rajasthan region
right
and uh what about the plants and animal
references? So plants in the rigida
include the bamboo, the lotus, various
kinds of Indian grasses and uh the
animals they include tigers and lions.
Imagine tigers and lions. Typical Indian
subcontinent. The Indian subcontinent is
the only place where we have tigers as
well as lions. Right? So we have tigers,
we have lions, we have the
uh capihi that is monkey, we have uh the
hustin or uba which is the uh elephant.
We also have leopards and so on. So that
these are the animals that we find
obviously in the Indian subcontinent,
not in central Asia, not in Europe, not
anywhere else. uh there are no the trees
that are discussed are also uh
subcontinental trees. We don't have
birch bark you know birch forests or
whatever that the kind of forest you
have in central Asia in the step region.
We don't have references to reindeers
and elks that is that is found up north.
We don't have references to aurora
borealis or or those you know climate in
the arctic regions. None of that. So
clearly clearly Indian conditions okay
within the sapasindu region mainly. You
put all of this together, it's clear
it's from Afghanistan to the north all
the way to Rajasthan in the south. The
aganga plains in the east all the way to
essentially Balojasthan in the west. So
that essentially is the region of the
riveda.
Nirvana Shank says, "I've always
wondered what were the origins of Japan
and its early society and how did the
Yamato rulers, Shinto traditions, and
early social structures come together to
shape the first political,
religious and cultural foundations that
influenced Japanese civilization for
centuries. Thank you for your attention
to this matter. Japan fascinating
civilization, fascinating culture, very
ancient roots of this culture, very
beautiful culture even today, deep
linkages with Indian civilization and
culture,
polytheistic culture, all of that,
right? Very similar to India in so many
ways, very 2,000 year relationship with
India also. So how did Japan start off?
Starts off like 2,000 3,000 maybe
several thousand BC. So Japan starts off
as
many small groups, many small pockets of
people on the Japanese islands. First of
all, let's look at the islands, shall
we? So what do the Japanese islands look
like?
So Japan is this archipelago
east of East Asia, right? This is Japan.
It's uh it's it's an archipelago. You
have the northern island, the great
island of Kaido. Then you have the kur
islands which are now part of the part
of uh um Russia. Then we have the major
island of Japan on which we have Tokyo,
Naga, Nagagoya, Osaka and so on. Then we
have Tokushima
uh this island here. Okay. Then we also
have this island here and a lot of other
islands like Yakushima,
like Toshima and we have Okinawa. Where
is Okinawa? This obviously is Okinawa
and it goes all the way to the outskirts
of Taiwan, Akettoi Island and Yunaguni.
So these are the Japanese islands and a
bunch of more islands they have all
around the place. Right. So that is
Japan. It's an archipelago. Where is
Tsushima? Tsushima.
This is Tsushima. And you had battles
here between samurai and Mongols.
Mongols belonging to the empire of Shri
Kublhan. And the Mongols lost Kublai
Khan not Chingis. Chingis never lost
thing. Kubla did his grandson. Now
coming back to Japan. So that is Japan.
So Japan starts off as many small groups
of people on these islands. Okay. And
over time one powerful group emerged the
Yamato. And they used religion Shinto
and the social hierarchy of Japan to
pull all these groups together into what
eventually became Japanese civilization.
So first of all you had a bunch of
people called the Jon people. Jon they
were hunter gatherers. They did hunting
and fishing and gathering of seaweed and
gathering of plants and all that and
they made these distinctive clay pots.
Let's take a look at the Jon clay pots.
Okay, let's quickly take a look at that.
Jon clay pots. Very famous.
Jon clay
clay pots. Very famous. Jon potterry. So
very distinctive, very um famous
pottery, Jon pottery. Okay. So the Jon
people uh made these very famous uh clay
pots and and the pottery and all of
that. Then you had people who came in
from the Asian mainland, East Asia,
Northeast Asia. U a bunch of people
called the Yayoi people, Yayoi people.
So they brought
new practices into Japan, into the
Japanese islands. uh metal tools, uh
weapons and rice farming, agriculture,
various kinds of agriculture, all of
that was brought into Japan by the Yayoi
people. So then you have the
introduction of rice farming in Japan.
So because of this you had people who
could settle down and and and this gave
rise to larger villages you know larger
villages and uh people started focusing
on irrigation and as a consequence some
communities became more powerful and in
larger and more powerful than others. So
you had all these different groups of
people. Typically these were clans.
Clans are extended families. They're not
tribes. They're extended families. So
you had all these different clans in
Japan with their own land, with their
own uh uh gods, with their own set of
gods, with their own warriors. So each
clan, each group of people would have a
separate set of gods that they would
worship. So it was a very polytheistic
uh system in Japan.
Then around about 3rd to fifth century
AD, one clan
emerged powerful, more powerful than the
others. This clan was called the Yamato
Yamato clans. So the Yamato leaders they
started they eventually initially were
just you know local chieftains.
Then they eventually started becoming
calling themselves kings and eventually
they became emperors. So they started
ruling over other clans slowly and
eventually the whole of Japan. So that
is uh how the Yamato took over in Japan.
So society in Japan was built around
these clans. Each clan had a small
chieftain. Each clan was small and each
had a chieftain who was the main priest
who was also the uh political leader and
society was hierarchical, upper classes,
lower classes, all of that. You know,
farmers, society needs to have
structure. Every society has structure.
So you had a a hierarchy in society like
every every other society in the world.
And most people they farmed rice and did
fishing and you know some would be
warriors and that sort of thing. Um so
early Japanese religion was called
Shinto. It was all about uh spirits.
Kami, you've heard the word kami kaz. Uh
the the storm of the gods or something.
Kami kaz, right? The divine wind. The
kami kaz is this this divine wind that
saved Japan from the Mongol invasions.
Not just one but two Mongol invasions.
The kami kaz. So kami means the Japanese
gods, Japanese spirits, nature spirits,
mountain spirits, river spirits, uh
ancestral spirits, storm spirits and so
on. These are the kami. So the Shinto
religion, the original religion of the
Japanese was all about various kami and
the the worship of kami. Each clan had
its own set of kami that they woripped.
And each clan would have its own
festivals, its own rituals to keep the
kami happy and to ensure that the clan
was protected from bad fortune and
whatever, right? And there was no holy
book. There was no prophet. There were
no rules. It was all about various local
customs and rituals and offerings.
Respect for your ancestors, respect for
nature. Sounds exactly like Hinduism,
not like Buddhism, right?
So that was the culture of Japan and the
Yamato uh rulers eventually they became
powerful and they claimed that their
ancestors were linked to very important
very powerful kami uh the sun goddess I
forget the name of the sun god goddess
and so on and so by by claiming by
making these claims they sought to make
their leadership seem more natural and
sacred just based on on the laws of
nature and all that um and this was the
beginning of the idea that the emperor's
family has divided divine connection,
divine protection, right? And the
emperor is the the son of God, that sort
of thing. And this became a core part of
Japanese political life and religious
life for centuries. And this is
essentially the foundation of Japanese
society, Japanese culture, Japanese
civilization. Eventually, you had the
idea in Japan of one central ruler, the
emperor who ruled over all the clans.
And eventually
sometimes you had a situation where the
emperor was ruler only in name and the
real power was in the hands of maybe
shogans or samurai you know that sort of
thing but the emperor was the embodiment
of the uh of of the rule of Japan and
that sort of thing. Uh so that is
essentially the forces that have shaped
Japan Shinto traditions. Um it's
Japanese society historically was about
uh villages that engaged in rice farming
and uh fishing and so on clan-based
society and then you had Yamato rulers
who built a centralized state and it was
all about Shinto beliefs about kami and
sacred ancestors and eventually you had
Hindu and Buddhist traditions coming in
from the west from China from India
through China and that was then
synretized into Japanese society and
culture and eventually the kami and the
Buddha they kind of became came together
and you had a whole bunch of Indian
deities that the Japanese started
worshiping is kami. One of the great
kamies was benzin right saraswati.
Another kami is uh kangitan that is uh
binayak and vinayak uh that is obviously
uh lord ganesh and every other Hindu god
or goddess was incorporated into the
pantheon of the kami.
So a lot of Hindu practices became
Shintoised. It was just a natural
it was a natural fit. Buddhism was more
artificially fitted into Japan but
Hinduism was a natural fit for Japan. So
that kind of is the story of of Japan
died with Pushian says who are the Kaks
how are they different from the average
Russian in Ukrainian? I have read about
their involvement in military battles
and conquests like Siberia and Kauass.
So when I was a kid, I had seen these
Kazak dancers and Kazak fighters. I
thought they were from Kazakhstan.
Kazakhstan was a part of the USSR,
right? But not quite. So
Kazaks.
So the Kazaks look like this. And the
Kazaks are Kazak squat is very
interesting. It's a great squat if you
are into you know exercise. The Kazak
squat. Kosak squat and the Kossac uh
dance. It's a very acrobatic dance,
right? This uh it's typically men who do
that, but apparently even ladies, but
it's typically men, soldiers who do the
who do the Kak dance, the dance of the
Kaks. It's a very spectacularly
acrobatic performance. So, uh as a kid,
as a as a child, I imagined that the
Ksaks were the Kazaks from Kazakhstan,
but it's not quite the case. So who were
the Kazaks? The Ksaks of Russia. Um
what's the origin of this word? It it
probably is from a Turk word that means
a free person or an adventurer. Okay. So
the the cosaks were people who lived in
the frontiers of Russia, the borderlands
of Russia. They lived very differently
from the standard, you know, regular
Russian and Ukrainian people. Okay? They
uh were mostly Slavic people, not
Turkish people, mostly Slavic people. Um
but they eventually became a separate
warrior community. They had their own
rules, their their own traditions. So
about 500 or 600 years before today they
for you know a bunch of people formed
groups on the borderlands on the step in
the step region of Russia and they
settled down in the region and they kind
of became the protection of Russia from
various you know outside groups like the
Tatars and so on so on. So the Kazaks
would settle in the borderlands and they
would they would protect the interior
parts of Russia from the outsiders from
the Tatars and other various wild
tribes. They would protect the farmlands
and the farmers from these nomadic
tribes. Okay.
And these cosaks were typically runaway
peasants who did not want to be under
the various feudal landlords who ruled
Russia. So they ran away and they moved
to the frontier and lived by hunting,
fighting, sometimes raiding other tribes
and so on.
So it's it's like people living your
regular village life to live on the edge
of civilization. It's kind of like the
wild west, you know, the the great push
westwards that you had in the American
uh in North America. That's what the
English did, right? Uh so they lived on
the edge of civilization. They were
armed, they were organized and uh kind
of like you know the frontier cowboys of
the Wild West. Uh so the Kossaks were
horsemen, they were fighters, they were
warriors. Their job was essentially
guarding the borders that they lived in
towns and villages and uh they used to
have a leader called a hetman or
something and they kind of had a warrior
democracy kind of kind of system. Um,
that's what it was, right? That's what
the Kazaks were. And u
they they they
had to be under the authority of the
Russian uh government of the Russian
Tsar and they defended the empire and
the Kossak typically was expected to
serve about 20 years in the service of
the Tsar and then they became free to do
whatever they want. Typically that was
the kind of uh you know obligation they
had to the empire. So they were they
were armed frontier warriors. They were
they had freedom but they also had a
tough military duty and they had more
freedom than the regular farmers and all
who were under the uh feudal structure
in Russia. So that is the Kazaks of
Russia.
Krishna of the Sur Netherlands says what
were the cultures and dietary habits of
the skitians like? Did they eat meat or
fish or were they vegetarian? They also
had batwash DNA. What were their
cultural similarities with barat
worship? Were they aas or were they
mletches and vatyas?
The shakas. We're talking about the
sakas. The shakas or the sakas
the the our Persian neighbors.
They called these people the sakas. We
call them the shakas.
So that's the uh skithian people. Now
what's the origin of the skithian
people? First of all, if you read any
history textbooks or any history, any
research paper in history about history,
they will refer to the Kithan people as
an Iranic people.
Iranic people. Now, what's older India
or Iran? And where did the Iranian
people come from originally? India,
right? Of course, once again, a lot of
historians won't agree with that, but
that's okay.
So the origin of the skithan people, the
skithian people, they lived in present
day central Asia and eastern Europe.
This huge territory it was calledya.
Let's Google skitia and see the see the
map of what skitia was like. The whole
of the region was Kitia.
Okay, huge huge vast region. Uh come on.
Do we have a better way of
this is the Indoskitians? But yeah, this
kind of is Kita.
Uh this is the western step actually.
Uh
shall we have to open Wikipedia? I
suppose we could kind of do that. Okay,
let's go to Wikipedia and try. It's
essentially central Asia and Eastern
Europe. That is
so here we have north of Anatolia.
region which is just a subset of skithia
actually. Androofago means cannibals.
Well, I don't think skithians were
cannibals but whatever. The Greeks may
have seen them as that. So yeah, this is
a better representation of what was and
you know para comes much later that is
present day Iran. Partha comes much
later but was this region for thousands
of years. Thousands of years. So that is
Kitia. Now who are the Skithian people?
What were their origins? Their origins
were most likely
some of these clans that ended up on the
losing side in the battle of the 10
kings. So more than 10 clans were
defeated by king sudas in the battle of
the 10 kings. It's the oldest battle
known in humankind human history. It's
in the riga. So the the clans that were
defeated were ejected out of India. They
were sent into permanent exile and that
was most likely the origin the origin of
the Indo-Uropean languages going
westwards out of India. One of the clans
was the parha clan which became the
Persians and many other clans went into
central Asia northern and west
northwards and westwards. Some of these
could have ended up as the skithians.
Skithan DNA very much of Indian origin
but eventually the Skiththian DNA
becomes very mixed because they met all
these different peoples different
peoples of different races all across
central Asia and Eastern Europe and so
on and they intermingled with them. So
eventually you have schan people who
look like Mongols or Turks. You have
skithian people who look like Europeans
with red hair or blonde hair and you
have skithians who look like Indians and
Persians also.
So because they traveled all across
central Asia and settled down all over
the place for like 3 4 5,000 years
that's why they acquired all kinds of
mixed genetics but originally they most
likely were of Indian origin. Uh were
the aras originally they were aryas but
eventually they became bletchers because
they stopped u you know they stopped
performing vic rituals I suppose and
started doing things that are not
allowed in the vedas. Eventually they
became wide and they became mchletchas I
suppose but their language remained
Indo-arian or Indo-Iranian right
uh what kind of culture did they
practice what kind of food they
would have eaten all kinds of food I
suppose they would have eaten meat they
would have eaten fish they were warriors
they were nomads they were huntsmen one
of their practices was the slave trade
which is definitely not a very area
trait
right if you engage in the slave trade
you cannot be called an ara You have to
be called a lecher, right? So, one of
the things the Skithians did was engage
in the slave trade in very very in a
very profitable way. It made them very
very prosperous and they had a lot of
gold, the Skithian gold. And uh they you
have various burial sites, kans and all
that which are still there and some of
these burials happen in in the frozen
tundra in the frozen steps of central
Asia where the bodies don't decompose.
So that's why we have skithan bodies.
So, and Skithian tattoos. So, let's
let's take a look at that. Okay. Skiian
mummies.
Skiian mummies.
Peric burials. So, this is an example of
a Peric burial. As you can see, this is
just person has blonde hair. Definitely
not very Indian, right? Clearly has
acquired foreign genetics. You can see
this person has tattoos, right? Tattoos.
Uh, Skithian warrior mommy was a
13-year-old girl. A 13-year-old girl was
a warrior.
Akitian mommy here. Another Skitian
princess with tattoos. Akitian gentleman
with a fascinating hairstyle and the
tattoos on the face.
Um and so on
another skitian person. This is a
skitian lady who has European features
because of interixing
and so much more. Skitian horsemen.
Uh, skitian ice maiden. Tajikian Tajik
no Iranian. So that's a different story.
Ties is a different story. And so on and
so forth. Skitian tattoos.
What is that?
Skitian tattoos. So interesting tattoos
you can find. These are modern
representations of various tattoos. Uh,
clearly a tattoo on somebody's thigh.
And this is a a human modern person with
skithian style tattoos on their body.
That sort of thing. This uh once again
is a modern person with that.
So yeah, very interesting tattoos some
of these u preserved bodies have. Uh so
that was a thing they some of the
skithians engage in slave trade. Not all
some of them did. the ones especially in
u
in in
Eastern Europe they did that uh cultural
similarities well they worshiped the sun
they were polytheistic so cultural
similarities religious similarities
um they I'm not aware of the them being
vegetarian
uh they defeated the Persians on various
occasions one of the skithian queens
Tamri
she defeated and killed Kurush
the Persian king Cyrus Kurush.
Yeah. And yeah, long story about the
about the Skithians. So that's about the
Skithians.
Okay. Amisha says, "Several photographs
of Iranian women before the Islamic
invasion circulate on the internet, but
I've seen people refute the view that
Iran was progressive by saying that this
was limited to a small rich elite in
Iran and that the great majority of
women had no substantial rights." What
is true is the question. It's a very
good question.
So, let's understand
Iran properly in the right context. Not
properly properly will take a lot of
time but in the right context we know
that Iran in the 20th century for a
while was ruled by the sha of Iran
Muhammad Raza Palvi who was a US puppet
and he sought to westernize Iran. So
let's let's quickly Google this.
Muhammad Raza Pahvi. How long did it his
Okay. Muhammad Raza Pahavi uh years
of rule
from where to where? Okay. From 1941 to
1979 and in between there was Muhammad
Mosad who was in power but yeah so let's
say this gentleman ruled for 40 years.
Okay. Let's say he ruled for 40 years
and he was a very westernized ruler. He
ruled for 40 years roughly. Before
Muhammad Raalvi who was very westernized
and liberal, Iran was under a certain
kind of
well culture
for about
1300 years.
What kind of culture? Islamic culture,
right? Islamic culture, Islamic
religion, Sharia law, a Turk rulers who
ruled Iran. Not Persian rulers, but
Turkish rulers who rule over Iran for
centuries. Nad Sha was a Turk. He was
not Persian. The the monster who invaded
India and massacred 100,000 people in
one day in Delhi. He came from Iran, but
he was Turk. He was not Iranian. He was
not Persian.
So Iran was under the rule of Turks just
like India was under under the rule of
Turks for centuries.
And the the the religion and and culture
that was imposed on Iran for 1300 years
was was nonarian. It was the Arabic
religion and culture. And in that
religion and culture, women are supposed
to be covered up and all all that stuff.
We know how it is, right? So that is the
culture that Iran has had for about 1300
years roughly,
give or take a century. That is a long
time to be under that sort of religion
and culture. Now Muhammad Pelvi tries to
change things and he is then in power
for 40 years. Do you think he can change
everything in 40 years and completely
transform the country? He can change
some things in some parts of Iran. In
the large cities he can make changes. So
what Palawi did is that he made it
mandatory for Iranian women to not cover
themselves with hijabs or borcas or
whatever. And this was mostly seen in
big cities like the mashad or whatever.
But in rural areas you can't enforce
this completely. So in rural areas the
1300 year old tradition continued. I
suppose in Iran he Muhammad Rai imposed
some restrictions on polygamy but did
not outlaw polygamy completely. He made
it legal for women to to receive
education.
Okay. He he he said women can receive
education, girls can receive education.
And so girls did get educated in certain
disciplines like nursing and whatnot.
Not all disciplines
but the overall Iranian society even
under Muhammad Isa was like they say
patriarchal male dominated women were
supposed to get married at a certain age
and so on so forth.
So it is in cities like Thran and so on
that women you know wore miniskirts
short skirts and you know western dress
and you had ladies on the beaches of the
Caspian Sea wearing uh swimsuits and
all. you had some of that but that was
in the big cities in the in the rural
areas you do not have all of that in the
rural areas life was still pretty
traditional.
Um
so the great majority of women still
lived as per the old traditions 1300
year traditions of Iran. In the big
cities you did try to make all these
reforms make all these changes and women
did have substantially more rights than
before for about 40 years.
But some of the changes that Palahi made
were seen as very drastic
like forcing women to uncover themselves
not wear hijabs or or burkas anymore. A
lot of women that's why because of this
forcible change that's why they
supported the 1979 Islamic revolution.
So it's complicated. 40 years isn't
enough time to transform a country which
has been under one set of laws and and
rules and culture for 1300 years. It's
you can't do that. Right. Um, so yeah,
you do see pictures of women in Iran who
look like they're dressed in a western
way and so on, but it doesn't tell you
the entire story. So the thing is both
pictures are true. Both claims are true
that women were given substantial rights
in Iran, at least on paper. And the
middle class women and upper class women
in the big cities of Iran, they did
enjoy a lot more freedom.
uh during this time but also a lot of
women chose not to you know partake of
these freedoms especially in the rural
areas and in many parts of Iran in the
rural areas these changes existed only
on paper but they were not they could
not be enforced
and then the traditional outlook of many
people in Iran it brought forth the
Islamic revolution also exacerbated by
the fact that Muhammad Rai was an
American stoogge so that is the
situation that is Uh it was complicated
there. It's it's not a black and black
or white kind of story. It was complex.
Okay.
What else do we have? Um real brother
Putin says was there any Christian
element in colonization? Of course.
Whether it is the Americas, whether it
is Africa, whether it is India, there
was a substantial Christian element in
colonization. Um the Spaniards, they
were out for plunder, but they justified
plunder through Christianity.
So they got this these papal bulls,
right? Um
what was it called?
I forget the name of the paper bulls,
but various papal bulls. A papal bull is
a declaration by the pope that you can
do certain things.
So these declarations they allowed the
Spaniards to go to there was this this
uh doctrine of terraulis
nulles a land that is inhabited by
non-Christians is an empty land
essentially okay
nullis nulio it's a Latin term meaning
nobody's land uh used in international
law to describe territory not under the
sovereignty of any state historically
European powers used this concept to
justify colonizing inhabited lands
inhabited lands by declaring them
legally empty or used disregarding
indigenous populations and their land
rights. So if you had a population that
was not Christian you could declare that
land as terra nulus and take it
and these these invaders they would come
with a lot of churchmen uh missionaries
who would then take the enslaved people
and convert them to Christianity and if
they converted to Christianity they
would be less brutalized. Okay. They
would maybe not be tortured to death.
Maybe maybe they would just be hanged
instead of being tortured to death or or
whatever. Yeah. So there was a very big
Christian element in colonization. I
mean look at Africa today. African
indigenous religions are hardly in
existence now in Africa. Okay. Let's
let's see the religious
uh religious demographics of Africa.
Religious demographics
not India. Africa.
Let's take a look at the map.
This this is what we have. Okay. Uh I
think this actually makes more this
makes more sense. You hardly have any
indigenous religion left in Africa. It's
mainly two foreign religions. Right? So
as you can see there was a very
Christian element in colonization and
the same there applies to other parts of
the world.
the the British colonizers came to India
first for trade but then they brought in
their missionaries who then started
writing atrocity literature and they
still they taught that atrocity
literature to us and that's now taught
to us in our education system that our
ancestors burned women alive our
religion is misogynistic patriarchal
backward primitive cast this that this
that all this atrocity literature was
created by the British they did all of
that and then this is all taught to us
today and that's why we have the UGC
issue and this cast issue and all of
that we are simp our government is
simply continuing in the great tradition
of the British of dividing Indian
society further. So all of these horrors
that exist in Indian society today, all
these issues that exist in Indian
society today is because of the Indian
inferiority complex that was imposed by
the British and the fact that our people
our leaders still believe what the
British taught us and all of that what
we were what the British taught us was
cooked up by the missionaries
to create problems and divisions in
India in Indian society. The objective
was to dismantle and destroy Indian
civilization which is a pro which a
project that's still undergoing today
and uh yeah
um okay we have crossed 2 hours and 4
minutes let's take maybe a couple more
questions uh Amisha says what happened
to the Greek settlements in India
central Asia and Bactria
um the Greek settlements so Alexander is
said to have uh founded a number of
cities called Alexandria
in u in India in Persia also one still
exists it is Alexandria al-iscandria in
Egypt but apparently he founded a number
of other Alexandrias in India and uh I
mean those parts of India that he did
kind of occupy for a while also in
Persia so the parts of India he occupied
were mainly Gandhara and syn and all
that right Gandhar so there is this uh
Alexandria in Gandh are the ruins of
which exist. Okay. Uh Alex
Okay. Okay. Okay.
Give me a second. Alexandria.
Alexandria in Gandhara.
H
what was it called? It was called Alin
Al something.
Alex, what is it called today?
Ah, Gandhara.
Tajikistan
border.
Uh, Tajikistan
What was it called?
I forget the name. Al something.
Uh,
okay. Afghanistan, Tajakistan border.
Afghanistan, Tajakistan border. Greek
ruined city.
What is it called? I kanum. Finally,
Ianum, right? I kanum. So kanum. So if
you go to the map um you'll find al i
kanum and it's on the border between
Afghanistan and Tajakistan. And you can
actually see the satellite image of
this. You can see that you know it's a
nicely welllaidout city. It used to be
but it no longer exists. So uh this city
was founded allegedly by Alexander.
Okay. And it was in existence even after
the demise of the Seucid Empire. So what
happened to Greek settlements like
these? You had Greek settlements in
Gandhara in Kashmir in Punjab
uh etc. What happened to these Greek
settlements? Well, they continued. They
continued. Some of these became
independent city states. Some of these
became part of the Indo- Greek kingdoms.
Some of these were in Bactria which is
northwest Afghanistan, Tajakistan and
Usbakistan. That is Bactria. That was
also extended India. Right? So you had
uh Greekactrian kingdoms there which
were Indianized eventually and you had
the Indogreek kingdoms which were in
proper Gandhar which is Afghanistan and
also uh Kashmir and northern Punjab. All
of that
and the Greek people were a small
minority
in these regions and eventually they
became Indianized. Eventually they lost
political power but they continued
existing there living there and they
eventually married into the in in
population and became Indianized and
eventually their descendants will not
even know that they are of Greek origin
and eventually the Greek cities some of
those were were abandoned some of these
continue. For example, you have a city
called Junagard in in in Sarah which
allegedly was originally Yavanagar which
was a Greek settlement. It is said that
the the city of Seial Court in Punjab
currently temporarily in Pakistan. It
was Shakala or something which was the
capital city of Milind the Milander. So
some of these cities still exist. Some
of the cities got abandoned for whatever
reason and the people simply assimilated
into the Indian society and uh their
descendants will today not even know
that they have some fractional Greek
ancestry.
Right. Uh I still have some more
questions but maybe I should um now go
and see what questions we have in the
chat. Okay, I can see we have 26 super
chats. That will be a while to take
those. So please stop taking super chats
and let me go through the super chats
now. Okay, Sagnik Achara has become a
new member. Thank you so much sir for be
becoming a member. Welcome to the
channel and thank you very much. Okay
says when you refer to multipolar world
you always mention the year 2016 with
respect to the US losing uniolarity.
What really happened during the time?
Thank you. Um when did I mention 2016
with the US losing uniolarity?
It's more like 2012 was more like 2008.
It's not 2016.
See the uniolar moment for the US
started in 1989 1990. That's with when
the USSR disintegrates. Okay? That's the
disintegration of the USSR when there's
only one superpower left, the US. So for
about 20 years, they were the only
hedgeimon in the world. Then you have
the the banking crisis 2008 and the
Chinese decided that now is our time to
start becoming a little more assertive.
In 2012 Xiinping comes to power and then
suddenly you have this wolf warrior
diplomacy of China. So China starts
bearing its fangs you know. So it's 2012
that the US suddenly realizes that China
is not what we expected expected it to
become. We thought China if it becomes
prosperous it'll become a democracy. But
now we are seeing China bearing its
fangs against us. China is behaving like
a wannabe imperial power. So the the
uniolar moment ends around 2012, not
2016. 2016 is the is Donald Trump coming
to power for the first time. No, that's
not it. It's 2012. The the period
between 2008 to 2012 is when China
changed or at least start that's the
period when China stopped hiding its
strength and biding its time. It's 20 in
2012 comes to power and he says it's
enough now. We have hidden our strength
enough. We have bid our time enough. Now
let's show who we really are. Maybe it
was premature of him to do that. But
yeah, it's around 2012 that you see a
change in the attitude and behavior of
China. And that's when we can say that
there's the beginning of a multipolar
world kind of
brown leprechaun says historically why
did many countries expel Jews? Well, you
see Jews first of all let me tell you
this before I talk about other
countries. Jews have been in India for
about 2,100 years.
About 100 BC is when you have the first
Jews who get shipwrecked on Indian tours
and they were allowed to settle down in
India and they lived in India for 2,100
years and then you had multiple more
multiple more waves of Jews who came
into India and settled into India. One
of these migrations to India was after
the Makabian riot, right? Makabian uh
revolt against the Roman rule over
Judea, the Roman occupation of Judea and
the destruction of the second temple of
Solomon and the number of Jews escaped
and fled to India and they also settled
down in India and you had multiple other
migrations of Jews to India. So Jews
have been living in India for about
2,100 years at least.
India never expelled Jews. India never
um oppressed Jews.
Jews were allowed to keep on practicing
their indigenous I mean their their
original religion.
Jews were never
asked to convert or to change their
lifestyle or whatever. So India never
did that to the Jews. Okay. India has
never shown any kind of anti-semitism to
the Jews ever.
When it comes to other countries, let's
say European countries, Jews have lived
in Europe for about 2,000 years, I would
say roughly, and they have been
persecuted all over the place. Every
single European kingdom, country,
empire has persecuted Jews. And Jews
have been accused of all kinds of uh
nasty things.
In some countries in Europe, they accuse
Jews of poisoning the wells. So whenever
there is an outbreak of plague because
the Europeans are dirty and not they
don't take bath
they accuse Jews of poisoning the wells.
So you are poisoning the wells and we
are drinking from the wells and that's
why we getting a plague the plague and
that's why we are all dying out. So the
Jews are responsible for that and they
would then go and massacre Jews. Then
they would accuse Jews of uh some blood
liel or something drinking blood of
children or something.
Okay. So that's another thing that Jews
were accused of doing.
Another thing that they would accuse
Jews of doing was to was of holding
wealth and stealing gold and clipping
coins and whatnot. So these accusations
were all over Europe but never in India.
If the Jews are tr truly so evil as the
Europeans have claimed for 2,000 years,
how come the Jews were never accused of
these things in India? How come? So it
makes no sense. It makes no sense. These
were all lies clearly because if Jews
are so evil as the Europeans claimed,
then they would have been as evil as
that in India also. But they were they
never did a thing in India.
They were the best guests for 2,000
years in India.
So clearly the Europeans were lying or
rather otherwise we are lying and we
were tolerating this nonsense. Clearly
we were not. So, so these are the
reasons why the Jews were persecuted,
oppressed, massacred, pogromed,
genocided over and over and over and
over again in in Europe. In Spain, it's
a whole different set of reasons. After
the reconista, even the Jews were
expelled from from Spain and many of
them those Jews came and settled in
India. Some of them at least and so on.
Yeah.
Uh Krishant Bordoy says some Polish MPs
were saying Epstein was a KGB agent.
Yeah. They try and push everything on
Russia. Very funny. It won't work this
time. Yeah, Epstein was a Russian agent.
Haha. KGB agent. Boy, very funny.
Uh MK says, "Bought most of the books
you recommended and absolutely love
them. Please keep the recommendations
coming. At least five books a week."
Well, if that is something you all would
want from me, I could keep doing
recommendations. Maybe five books a
week. Anyway, I'm I'm so glad that you
actually bought the books and read the
books I recommended and you love them.
very happy to hear this and I'll be
happy to recommend more. So, thank you.
Geo Warrior says, "Why can't Trump use
the NATO framework to protect Greenland
from Chinese or Russian influence
instead of trying to invade it?" Well,
Trump
there's a there's an element of
megalomania to Trump. There's an element
of ego to Trump, isn't it? Trump isn't
out there to protect everybody. Trump is
out there to prove to the world how
great he is.
He wants to be remembered as the
greatest, biggest, baddest American
president of all time. Bad as in
Muhammad Ali bad. I'm the baddest man on
the world on the planet. That sort of
thing. Baddest as in greatest. So Trump
wants to be wants to be remembered as
the greatest American president. One of
the ways to be remembered as the
greatest president is by expanding
American territory. How many American
presidents have done that? Very few.
There's the Louisiana purchase, there's
the Alaska purchase, and that's about
it. How about the Greenland purchase or
the Greenland acquisition? So he doesn't
see all these stories he's telling about
Russian influence, Chinese influences,
these are just excuses. He just wants to
expand American territory. So that's
what he's actually after.
Hers says what diet Rajputs, Barata and
Muggals used to have and what gave them
stamina to fight the war for months and
months and what workouts they used to
do. We have no idea because none of this
was recorded. I suppose um look
uh do we have any
workout routines that have been
preserved? No.
As far as I know, we don't know what
workouts they did. Um obviously the
Rajboards and Maratas would would
obviously practice sword fighting. They
would practice horse riding. They would
practice various martial arts. Um they
would do that. They would not go to the
gym and lift weights and do you know
military presses and lateral raises and
deadlifts and all. They would not do
that. They would do more functional
exercises like you know actual fighting
martial arts. That's what Maratas and
Rajput would have done. The Rajput art
of sword fighting is almost extinct.
Some of it you can still see in the in
dance forms. The Gujarati danda
dance, dandy ras, it actually originates
in Rajput sword fighting, the chhatria
sword fighting, right? Sword fighting.
Um, and so on. So, some of that kind of
survives. But what diet would they have
had? The Rajputs definitely ate a lot of
meat. Maratas, I suppose they also ate
meat. Uh, but what specific diets did
they have? Diet plan and all we don't
know. So, can't really answer because we
have lost all the records. The muggles I
am no expert in muggle history so I
can't say sorry.
Ishank Ishank Bija says do you think a
10 or 15 trillion dollar economy will
solve the problems of pollution women
safety and town level infrastructure?
You can solve these problems even today
with a $4 trillion economy. You just
need the right right leadership. Even if
you become a $20 trillion economy, you
still won't be able to solve the issue
of pollution, uh, infrastructure, dirt,
dust, garbage, lack of civic sense, all
of that. You won't be able to solve it
if the country remains allegedly corrupt
and with poor leadership. Allegedly,
even
with a $4 trillion economy, you can
solve this problems.
Pollution, of course, that is easier
said than done because if you want to
develop as a if you are a developing
economy, if you want to become a massive
industrial power, you've got to pollute
a bit. There's no other way out of it.
Look at London in the 1950s and60s. They
could not breathe the air in London.
The US was super polluted until the
1970s and 80s. Then they exported all of
their trash and garbage and pollution to
third world countries. That's why the US
is so clean today. So you can't really
solve all the problems but when it comes
to civic sense when it comes to
infrastructure when it comes to women's
safety
overall India is very safe for women
most more safer than many western
countries but there are some parts of
India where you you have issues now why
is that I'll not go into that
why some parts of India have issues
we'll not go into that but all of this
can be solved using with this just the
right leadership
died with preotion says did you see
small that the clip of Zaharan Mamani in
which he claimed that Modi slaughtered
Muslims in Gujarat to such an extent
that there are no Muslims left in
Gujarat anymore continued I have not
seen that continued despite Gujarat
having uh more Muslims in the entire US
none in audience fact checked that and
instead started clapping is the US
turning into a more and more propaganda
society
see this Mandani guy is an enemy of
India okay his mother was of Indian or
is of Indian origin Punjabi Uh what
mayor
Miranayer
uh whatever but Zoran is is more of a
Pakistani than an Indian. He hates India
um and he makes all these false claims
accusations and uh his audience is the
lefties lefties of the US and the US
also has this policy of of containing
India and they have no great love for
India. India is this evil polytheistic
culture, right? How dare India still
exist? How dare this polytheistic
culture still exist? So whatever
propaganda will be thrown against India,
they will wrap it up and they'll they'll
applaud that. Uh so yeah, it's it's
definitely a highly propagandized
society. Western media is just
propaganda
prop the best form of prop propaganda is
97% truth and 3% lies sprinkled in like
salt. That's the best form of propaganda
and that's what the US excels at. So it
is a very propagandized society for
sure. Yes.
Aush
Aush Gigu says, "Big fan of yours."
Thank you. Been following you since your
Chingisan video back in 2021. Thank you
so much. Thank you so much very much
indeed. Taking inspiration for you from
you. I am also currently creating AI
videos storying telling the stories from
Raja Tarangini. I hope to meet you
someday and talk about everything. I
would love to. Well, that is a great
initiative you have taken.
I really appreciate people who who
create things who create something. You
got to start from somewhere. So uh you
are creating AI videos telling the
stories from the Rajarangi. AI is a
great tool if used properly, if used
well, if used for the right purposes. Uh
it has given so much freedom
um and creative and and and and so much
of a creative outlet to people who
otherwise would not have had the
creative tools to do things. So I am
very happy that you are doing this.
Please
please continue that
stories from Kalahana's Rajat Tarangini.
Kalahana was a Kashmiri historian and
chronicler from about a thousand years
ago and he wrote the Raj Tarangini which
is a chronicle of all the kings of
Kashmir and India up to the time of his
um of his existence
and very interesting stories you'll find
in there. So yeah, you're you're telling
stories from that. So I'm I'm really
glad to glad that you're doing that.
Thank you very much for having me been a
longtime follower and I certainly hope
to meet you myself in the future someday
and discuss what's what we're doing. So
thank you so much and I wish you the
greatest of success. Thank you. Aayosh
Katos says Ktos Arya Vertavasi says how
did Indo Iranian central Asia excluding
Tajjakistan become Turk by culture and
massive genetic replacement give
statistics and further when further
readings I don't have statistics right
now with me I'm doing a live interaction
with you all how will I have statistics
but I'll tell you how it happened how
did this happen so like we discussed a
few minutes ago in the question about
skitia and the skitia
The whole of central Asia was once
called skitia for several thousand
years. It was inhabited by this
continuum of nomadic peoples who all had
the same original culture which was
Indian culture, Indo-arian culture,
Arian culture and they eventually moved
all settled in various parts of central
Asia and they practiced various kinds of
lifestyles. They intermingled with
various central Asian u uh you know u
population groups. Some started looking
Mongolic, some started looking European,
some had some had, you know, blonde
hair, some had white skin, some had more
more East Asian features. Many of them
had Indian and Iranian Persian features
and so on. So that was
mostly
of Indo-Iranian origin these people.
Then what happened is about 2500 years
ago there was a sudden eruption
from present day Mongolia this sudden
outward eruption of this new ethnic
group the huns.
The hoons were the
essentially the ancestors of the Turk
peoples as well as the Mongolic peoples.
The hoons suddenly
explode out of Mongolia and go
westwards, northwards in all directions
and uh they then put a start these
karnets and kaganets in various parts of
central Asia etc. And uh they defeated
the skitians and replaced and displaced
the skithians to a large extent in
central Asia. the horns and at the time
when we had the Gupta Empire in India
and you had the Huns attempted to invade
India they launched wave after wave of
invasion of India during the time when
Scandupta was our emperor at that same
time the Hoons were trying to invade
Rome successfully so that's how
widespread the Huns became and they were
so powerful and so on that they
essentially uh displaced and replaced
the Skians so if you look at the
inhabitants of nations like Kazakhstan,
Tajakistan etc. today they will have
some Skithian ancestry and a lot of Turk
ancestry if you go to East Turkiststan
or so-called sing today present day
occupied by China the people there are
like 50% Indian 50% Turk okay the people
of Singang uh for example let's take a
look at the people of Kashgar okay let's
see Qashqar
people
what do they look Like as you can see
they look like half Indian half Turk
right that's the people of Kashgar some
will look more Turkish some will look
more Indian some will even look uh you
know more more
Tajaki or whatever so Ugur people how
about them Ugur
so once again Ugur people will so will
show all these different kinds of uh
phenotypes
they will look like a mix between
Indians and Europeans and Turks. So
that's essentially what happened.
Typically the Uigor their female
ancestry will be Indoskitthian male
ancestor will be Turk. Statistics and
further readings you can look it up
yourself. I don't have the this off of
off the tip of my tongue but yeah. Vir
Kamat says on your podcast with Sir
Suresh Javan he claimed the US and China
are the same entity two sides of the
same coin. Could you explain this? book.
He can explain this. I can't explain
what my guests say. I am not responsible
for everything my guests claim. I do not
necessarily I'm not necessarily going to
agree with everything my guests say. I
give them a platform because they are
important people. They have valuable
perspectives and insights, but I I may
not necessarily agree with everything
they say. Right? So I I'm I don't
remember exactly what he may have
claimed and want explanation he should
be the one giving explanation not me
right I can't explain that
vin says if Iran falls Russia exhausts
China in India burn in war under US
direction by 2047 could Anglo rule rise
openly democracy fading London crowned
queen mother or lucy lawless style well
that's a fascinating picture you've
painted over here if Iran falls Russia
exhaust in China India go to war why
Why? Why? Why? Why? Why? If Iran falls,
why will China and India go to war? If
Iran falls, it makes even less sense for
India and China go to to go to war. If
Iran falls, why will Russia get
exhausted?
If Iran falls, how does it logically
lead to the consequences that you've
outlined here? Russia gets exhausted,
China, India go to war under US
direction. China and India will be
suicidal if they go to war under US
direction.
Yeah. Iran could fall. the Americans
have the capability to make Iran fall
for sure. But if that happens, it is
even more likely that ra come together
rather than rather than going to war
with each other. So um so it Iran if it
hypothetically falls it doesn't
logically give rise to the uh scenarios
that you have painted and yeah so I
certainly hope that doesn't happen.
Dirj Kamat says it appears that the US
and its master use occult practices
ranging from benign which is remote
viewing to barbaric which is human
sacrifices to attain geopolitical
miracles. Now uh you know remote viewing
is something that we hear that the CIA
and whoever they were kind of they had
programs to develop these capabilities
in some people or whatever remote
viewing and uh astral projection and
whatnot. Um, I haven't looked into these
things. There these horrific programs
like MK Ultra and whatnot. Once again, I
have not studied in detail, but I've
heard very very horrible things about
those things. Um, human experimentation
on their own people and so on. Um, all
kinds of nasty things they did to their
own people. And uh it looks like the
current American uh rich and famous and
powerful people they practice various
barbaric things like pedophilia and
child
whatever else right the epsteile stuff
uh but is it with the objective of
attaining geopolitical miracles or is it
some other set of objectives I don't
know I simply look this is a culture
that is alien to me this is not Indian
culture this is western culture I am not
an expert. I'm in this aspect of western
culture.
This is obviously something utterly
barbaric.
So why are they doing it? Will it really
I mean does it actually give rise to
geopolitical Americans? I'm not sure
about that. But it's something that I
don't understand. Oh
Namitana says if Iran falls isn't whole
energy
will be put on India via covered in
overt two-front war in internal problems
will we deal with it are we going South
Africa away to surrender our nukes or
have iron fist
if Iran falls isn't whole energy will be
put on India via covert and overt to
frontront war and internal problems
I am not able to understand the cause
and effect between this and that. If
Iran falls,
whole energy. Okay. Oh, the you not you
don't mean energy as in oil. You're
talking about America's focus and energy
and attention
will be now focused on India covered in
over. Yeah. Yeah.
A lot more. A lot more. If Iran is made
to fall and it the US
gets to control Iran after that, after
regime change, then they will be really
free to focus on India and China and
Russia. only three big pieces left and
the easiest piece will be India, not
Russia, not China. So yeah, not two
front like five front war they will do
on India
internally,
right? Can India deal with it? It will
be difficult for India to deal with it.
If Iran falls, it becomes more likely
that India will get vasalized.
Surrender of nukes or not, which way we
get vasalized is a different story. But
if Iran falls, it is really really bad
for India. Which is why Iran must not
fall. But it's not in our hands. It's
not in our hands. We can't even stop a
regime change in Pakistan, East
Pakistan, West Pakistan or Nepal. So how
can we stop a regime change in Iran? All
we can do is become more resilient
internally. But for that we need reforms
in India. Where are the reforms in
India? We are seeing more divisions in
Indian society being created by the
government.
What can I say? Vidhi manar says sir how
can you say no trade deal has been
signed
I say it because I have not seen any
signing of trade deal okay I don't know
what
okay let's ask Google this okay has a
India EU trade deal been signed
yes the India and EU announced the
conclusion of negotiations for a
comprehensive free trade agreement and
this has been signed.
Has a India US trade deal been signed?
Areai
signed? Question mark.
Where's your Google AI? What happened to
the Google AI? It died. Did it? Has
Okay, let's go to AI mode. Has a India
US trade deal been signed? A landmark
trade deal has been agreed upon in
principle. A formal legal agreement has
not yet been signed. It has not been
signed.
Something has been agreed upon in
principle. Whatever that means, it is
not a legal thing. You have to have the
agreement being signed on paper by both
sides.
That's why I say it has not been signed
because it has not been signed. Vidi G,
how do you imagine it has been signed?
Where have you seen the signing
ceremony?
Because Donald Trump tweeted something,
does it mean something? It it has been
signed. Has the Indian Minister of Trade
or the Indian Prime Minister put pen on
paper and signed some kind of legal
document? He has not. That's why I say
it has not been signed.
How have you been imagining that
something has been signed? You got to
pay more attention, ma'am.
Financial adviser says, "Was Indian
rupee devalued in 1966?" I don't
remember. I don't remember. Look it up.
It was devalued. It did have a bad
effect on India. But why did Mrs. Gandhi
do that? I don't remember right now. We
can look it up. ICMBB says why did the
Rajiv Gandhi's IPKF fail in Sri Lanka.
The IPKF, Indian peacekeeping force was
the Indian military,
the professional military. It was sent
into Sri Lanka to do the job of a police
force. Professional soldiers in the
professional military. When do they
succeed? They succeed when you have a
clear mission with a clear objective and
a clear time frame.
Go to so and so place,
do so and so thing in this many this
many hours and get the hell out.
That is a military operation. Or you go
do so and so thing, hold the place and
then further reinforcements will come
and so on and so forth. That's a
military operation. That's what the
military is designed to do. They were
given no military
mission, no clear objectives, no rules
of engagement. Just go and be there. Go
and be there. And lots of things you
can't do. Can't shoot at civilians. You
can't shoot at so on so forth. And
what's the what's the definition of of
a hostile operative?
There was so much ambiguity. There was
no clarity.
Then essentially the the army was just
asked to go and be there go and be there
but don't do anything essentially
that doesn't work so because of
mismanagement because of extremely poor
leadership that's why the mission failed
godliness says Indian state is blessed
with tourist attractions it's full of
wonders but sadly behavior of some
individuals towards foreign and even
domestic tourists is very unwelcoming
especially for
Why do we have issues in India? Why do
we have poor civic sense? Why do have we
have why do we have people who have this
massive inferiority complex? Why do we
have some people who uh behave badly in
public, who behave badly towards
tourists and so on and so forth? Why is
that? Why is the average Why is the
quality of the population so poor on
average? Why is that?
First of all, there's the issue of
illegal infiltrators who are on Indian
territory. They will not share our
culture. First of all, that's one aspect
of the problem. Who there are millions
of them. In 2016, Siri Kiran Riuju said
in parliament that there are at least 20
cr Bangladeshes in India.
2016. Today is 2026.
20 cr is sorry not 20 cr two 2 cr.
That's 20 million. 20 million.
Imagine the chaos that can How many
Rohingyas do we have? How many cookies
do we How many what else do we have?
Pakistanis. That's one aspect of the
problem. Many of these people are the
are the people who create the problems
and make India look bad even though they
are not Indian. The other thing is the
average Indian person is a the the
Indian population overall on average is
of low quality. Poor behavior, poor
civic sense, poor this, poor that, poor,
everything, low standards. Why?
The quality of your population depends
on the quality of your godamned
education system. India's education
system is garbage. It is trash.
That's why we have a very poor quality
population. That's that's the answer. To
solve these issues, you have to fix the
education system. Teach these things
from the time you are 5 years old.
Teach civic sense in practice.
Teach good behavior in practice, not by
by writing essays in a in practice.
Right? The quality of your population
depends on the quality of your education
system. Your new education policy is not
going to solve any of your problems.
Godliness says, "What is the history of
tourism? Did it start with trade or just
expedition?" I don't the history of
tourism.
Tourism historically would have had
tiatras in India. I suppose India was
full of these pilgrimage places and even
in the Mahabharat and Ramahayan there
are there are accounts of tiatras. That
is a form of religious tourism isn't it?
Many of these tiratas happened by you
know crossing forests which was very
difficult. Some of theatras happened by
by sailing on rivers which is very
pleasant. So I think
tourism happens only when you have
wealthy populations. And the in the
ancient world the wealthiest population
was in India. So I suppose India would
have been the place where tourism first
started and foreigners would come to
India as immigrants not as tourists but
Indians would travel the subcontinent in
maybe if they were wealthy and they
wanted to uh see different cities or
maybe if they wanted to for example do
pilgrimages. If you are living in let's
say southern India but you want to visit
the great juttering of kaash
um
not kash the kash is the mountain but
even kash mountain in Tibet I mean
that's that's religious tourism so I
suppose that could be the origins but
the history I'm not really sure
okay CS19 Jin says hello the trade deal
announced it's not announced it is
claimed nothing has been signed nothing
has been signed some announcement was
made by Trump but he has made an
announcement which is unacceptable to
India.
Where has it been signed? Something was
announced. Even Modi said some nice
words but nothing has actually been
inked.
Okay. So uh you've been noticing the
past five six months of Trump drama that
has exposed several prominent
Indian-Americans who claim to support
India but kept on undermining the
government of India.
These Indian-Americans
ask yourself one question. What passport
do they hold?
They hold the American passport, not the
Indian passport. They are citizens of a
foreign country. They may have the same
blood as you. They may have the same
ancestors as you, the same origins, the
same accent as you. But they are
American citizens. They will support
their country.
Unlike the Israeli Americans who support
Israel more than the US, possibly some
of them at least, Indian-Americans will
talk nice things, say nice things about
India, but their actions will all be
either neutral or essentially not very
beneficial to India. Please understand
one thing. If you want to understand a
person, what they truly all are all
about, ignore their words and focus only
on their actions. That will show you the
truth of a person.
So yeah, it has exposed several
prominent Indian-Americans and lots of
Indians are all heartbroken about it.
Why? Why are you heartbroken?
Be realistic about the world. Everyone
is selfish.
People will support you only if you're
powerful. India needs to get more
powerful. The Indian-Americans, most of
them will are are fair weather friends.
Not all but most of them. Uh yeah but
but once again my point is this trade
deal has not been signed. Trump has made
an announcement.
If India agrees to the to the claims he
has made in the announcement we become a
vasal state. So obviously we will not go
along with that. So the trade deal has
not been signed. There are still
differences between the two sides on the
trade deal. What Trump wants we can't
give him. So I don't think it's going to
happen very soon. The trade deal. A YT
user says, "Why do you think the
landscaping is so poor in India? I live
in an expensive part of Bangaluru yet
broken sidewalk, uncovered dirt and dust
everywhere. All cities look like a war
torn place. This is so sad." Okay. Now,
I will not talk about Bangaluru. I will
say imagine some hypothetical
metropolitan city in India which
actually is fictional. Okay? I'm not
talking about any any real city. I'm
talking about let's say we have some
hypothetical metropolitan city in India
and it's a fantastic place as in all
these multinational corporations are
there very highly salaried people live
there but it's horribly congested the
streets are very narrow uh there's dust
everywhere there is cement dust
everywhere there is natural dust
everywhere there is trash everywhere the
sidewalks are uncovered
There's no lawns or grass anywhere.
Everything looks like a vorton place. Uh
there's no traffic rules.
There are slums all over the place.
Illegal slums on public land. Why is it
like this?
Why is it like this in this completely
hypothetical fictitious city of India?
Why is it like this? Well, my answer is
corruption.
That's it.
I'm not talking about Bangalore. Okay.
I'm talking about a hypothetical
fictional city.
Naven Chawan says, "First time after
independence, we are witnessing such
anger and resentment in whole Hindi
heartland, Rajasthan, Madhya Pradesh,
Uttar Pradesh, Himachal Pradesh,
Uttarakand, New Delhi from general
category is 25% population's crime is
that they are they don't protest, unite
and transactional
Um, is it a crime to be part of the
general general category? The crime is
cast based reservations. That is the
crime against India. It's a crime
against Indian civilization.
The objective
of any good leader should be to unite
people and to remove the diff artificial
differences that have been, you know,
inserted in in our society. not to make
the differences worse, not to exacerbate
exacerbate the differences. A leader's
job is to unite, not divide.
So the crime
is castbased reservation.
Being born in so certain category is not
a crime.
Right? This is terrible what we are
seeing. Not I'm not saying that this
anger and resentment is terrible. I'm
saying that these new rules are being
brought in to further divide Indian
society and to paint the general
category as permanent oppressors and the
other categories as permanent victims.
That is a crime. That is apartheid.
India is a hindu phobic aparthide state.
That is the crime.
Feels strong man says recent Jesh Gangan
podcast was your best in last six months
reminds me of good old TRS podcast raise
a sharp Q&A and avoid repetitive
questions that you answer here every
week I'm glad you liked it yeah I've
done a bunch of podcasts recently I
thought let me go and accept um a few
invitations and yeah it was fun and J
was a great host so I'm glad you liked
it thank you
godliness says when geopolitics becomes
a tool for domestic political PR. You do
injustice towards your country. Indo US
trade deal is just one adjusted business
contract slightly tilting towards US and
no master stroke.
There is no US India trade deal thus
far.
Nothing has been signed. I don't know
why I think your media has made you
think that a trade deal has been signed.
I don't think it is the fault of Indian
people that they believe that trade deal
has been signed and it is already
you know in force. I think it is your
YouTubers, it is your news readaders, it
is your media that is misleading you.
There is no trade deal as of today.
Trump has made some claims. Modi made a
put out a tweet you know thanking him
but not agreeing to any of those things.
Where's the trade deal?
So this trade deal doesn't exist as of
today. There's no trade deal. What Trump
has claimed is is is a very unequal
unbalanced trade deal which we simply
can't accept. If we accept it then we go
back to the old East India Company days.
We can't accept it. The trade deal has
not happened. It has not been signed. It
is your stupid media, your stupid news
readaders, your stupid YouTubers who are
misleading you all.
Soldier boy says, "Sir, tell us about
the dark forest theory. Imagine you are
living in a gigantic forest, very thick
forest, trees everywhere and trees which
are very high, very tall and very thick
vegetation up there in the trees. So
thick that very little sunlight comes
down to the floor of the forest of the
jungle. You live in the jungle. There
are all kinds of dangerous animals in
the jungle. the tigers and scary um cats
and tigers and snakes and hilas and god
knows what other species of scary
predators exist there. Let's say you are
a person who lives in this forest. Does
it make sense to advertise your
existence? Hey listen everybody, I'm
here. Does it make sense? No. They'll
come and eat you. Right? So what you do
if you live in a dark forest is you stay
hidden. You stay quiet. You live your
life very quietly. You don't advertise
your existence. You do that in a dark
forest. In a scary dark forest. We live
in the solar system
on a small unregarded little planet on
the solar system. In the solar system,
the entire universe out there is like a
dark forest. Who knows what kind of
scary species of aliens live out there?
Do you want to advertise your existence?
Hey guys, I'm here. We are here. Listen,
we are here. at least come play as a pay
as a visit. Does it make sense? If they
are able to if they have the capability
to cross interstellar space thousands of
light years and visit you, do you think
they will let you live in peace? Their
capabilities will be way ahead of yours
technologically, right? Does it make
sense for you to advertise your
existence to somebody who is so
technologically more advanced than you?
No. Maybe your planet has resources they
seek. Maybe you are a nuisance for them.
Then stay hidden. behave like you are a
timid little species in a dark forest.
That's the dark forest theory.
Vihang Kurana says uh I'm I'm very well.
How are you sir? Nihang, why did
Buddhism in India evolve towards such
strong emphasis on a hinsa? Like while
in other religions Buddhist while in
other regions Buddhist traditions seem
to have evolved in alignment with local
martial arts or indigenous traditions.
Why did that happen is the question.
Why did Buddhism focus so much on a
hinsa?
Even in Tibet, Buddhism has focused on a
hinsa, which is why Tibet is now under
Chinese occupation. Right? But if you
look at
Japan, for example, the samurai are
classified as Buddhist, right? They did
not eat meat. They only ate fish. They
abhor beef. Beef eating was taboo in
Japan.
But they were warriors.
They had this warrior ethos code called
bushido
right the samurai and they were
frighteningly good warriors. The ninjas
were also Buddhist been classified as
Buddhist. So how come Buddhism allowed
that in Japan but in India it was
ainsik. What about Thailand? In Thailand
in m national martial art is the uh
sepak. No not sepak. Sorry.
Thai kick. What is it called? Muay Thai.
Muay Thai. Right. I mean that is a
pretty violent sport. It's a Buddhist
sport. In Cambodia you have Cambodian
blood sport which is a very violent
martial art. And so why is it that in
India we have such a very ains oriented
Buddhism? I'm not really sure
I've beats me. Why is it like that?
And that obviously led to the very rapid
fall of Gandhar because Gandhar was
primarily Buddhistic when the Goris
thing when the when the Turks came and
invaded right so wherever you had
Buddhism there was a very rapid fall to
the invaders and the very rapid
conversion to Islam but where you had
the other forms of dharma like Hinduism
uh did not work that well I'm not sure
why Indian Buddhism evolved towards a
hinsa so strongly
not sure maybe we
I'm Not sure. I'm not an expert in
Buddhism and I I don't really know why
it was this way. Anyway, Sam the Gamer
says, "Please restart insightful
geostrategy show. It was a gem. Diamond.
Really? You all want me to do that? I
could take it seriously perhaps.
Restarting it."
Okay.
Dark Side of the Moon. DSOTM says, "You
said Jews were India's best guests, but
the Cassoon family got rich from British
colonialism and opium trade. Explain the
role and how it fits." It doesn't really
fit does it? Well, look, there are
always exceptions. Why don't you people
understand that statistically what I am
saying is correct, but there is always
going to be some outlier statistically.
The Cassoons came from Baghdad. They
were Baghdad, the Jews that came that
came much much much later. They were not
the Jews that came 2100 years ago. They
were not the Jews that came to India in
the aftermath of the u uh the the the
Roman destruction of the second temple
of Solomon.
They were not the Jews that came in the
aftermath of the expulsion of the
Sephardic Jews from uh Iberia after the
reconista. The Baghdadi Jews were from
Iraq from Baghdad and they were brought
in by the British occupiers of India. So
the Sassoons are outliers. They're not
statistically part of the the group of
Jews I'm talking about. There's always
some exceptions.
But please understand that statistically
what I have said is absolutely correct.
The Europeans made all these horrific
claims about the Jews. The Jews were
poisoning wells. The Jews were drinking
blood of people. The Jews were clipping
coins. Did the Jews do any of that in
India? The Cassoons are an exception.
Statistically you will say that India is
a very peaceful nation but you still
have criminals in India right but does
it mean that a few criminals make India
makes India a criminal society? Please
think of it in a proper way. There's
always going to be some exceptions to
anything you say but that doesn't prove
anything.
So the Cassoons have their own story.
The Cassoons did a well plenty of nasty
stuff. No question about that. D with
Priosian says Mir Shramer said US uni
uniolarity ended in 2017. What's my
opinion?
I would say it started in 2008 2012.
Professor John Mir framer has his own
views. That's fine. The way I see it,
the situation changed between 2008 to
2012.
2012 we have the sudden emergence of
China in the sense that China abandoned
its hideand bite policy. It said now we
are the big deal. We are wolf warriors
and we will no longer
um take everything lying down. We're
going to give it back. So I and they did
this because they knew that they now
mattered the Chinese right.
So uh in 2014 you have the Russians now
taking a stand in Crimea. So I think
between 2008 to 20124 that's when
uniolarity ended.
Uh brown leprechaun says a short video
on Muslim Brotherhood please. I am no
expert on the Muslim Brotherhood. I I
don't study these topics so I am not the
right person for this. I I don't know
about the Muslim Brotherhood. I of
course know the basics
alazar university al kaira and so on but
I'm no expert on this and it's it's not
a topic that interests me a lot this one
so maybe not this one maybe something
else but anyway thank you for the
recommendation Aaron says Harun Aaron
says around 2008 China had the same GDP
as what India has today yet we seem to
have not as yet we seem to not have as
good infrastructure why is that The case
answer once again alleged corruption,
democracy,
leadership.
These are the answers. These are the
problems
which
have ensured that despite having the
same GDP essentially as China, we are so
far behind what the Chinese were in
terms of infrastructure
in 2008. How can we change that? by
changing the system, by eliminating the
alleged corruption and by having better
leadership.
Lack of vision also lack of vision.
It's a combination of democracy,
alleged corruption. Um I'm not not
talking about the top leadership. I'm
talking about state level, city level,
municipal level leadership and lack of
vision. That's the problems. So how do
you change this? You crack the whip and
you punish anybody who is guilty of even
the slightest corruption. They punish
them in the harshest way where the
Chinese would punish them possibly or
maybe not. Whatever guaranteed
punishment
that's the solution.
Okay. Abhirkar Abhir Shwkar says is
Indian spirituality sometimes adopted as
a way to avoid confronting reality
rather than engaging with it? A lot of
people may possibly think of it that
way. A lot of people will think that you
know um Indian spiritual Indian
spirituality is about becoming passive
becoming u non-interactive with the
world retreating into a shell uh
escaping from reality
right
see a lot of Indian spirituality is
about meditation
closing your eyes retreating into the
inner world in inner consciousness
forgetting about the world the objective
is to attain nirvana
the the end of the cycle of rebirths.
It's all about getting rid of your
attachments. Sounds very renunciative of
the real world, right? It's all about it
sounds like it's all about detaching
from reality, escaping from reality. The
truth is that it is indeed the case that
Indian spirituality says that this is
the highest thing you should aspire for.
But it also says it's not for everybody.
It's maybe for one or two% of the
population. Most people aren't built for
this. So there are other ways of being
spiritual,
right? It's not just about hut yog is
about asas and postures. It's not just
about raj yog.
It's also about bacti yog. It's also
about kria yog. It's al also also about
ghani yog. You can do various there are
different ways of becoming more
spiritual. You can become more spiritual
by being more engaged with the world but
in an ethical and moral way in a dharmic
way. So it's you see if you the way
these so-called fake gurus like Deepak
Chopra and all they explain of his
spirituality it's in a in a very very
distorted way
you can be very you can be a warrior and
be spiritual what did Sri Krishna tell
Arjun go kill them all don't escape
don't try to escape and run away from
your duty
do your job do your duty go kill them
All they are your cousins kill them all.
That is your
that's your duty that's your karma right
even by doing that by doing your duty
you can be spiritual so Indian
spirituality is way more nuanced and
complex than this one-dimensional BS
that deep chopra likes types are are
peddling to the world
died with priosin says moral collapse if
Iran sunk australian
career with multiple missile moral moral
collapse If Iran sunk Australian carrier
with multiple missiles, has that
happened
or are you painting a hypothetical
scenario? Uh Iran Australia, what
happened?
Um
has something happened? No such thing
has happened. Okay. Um yeah, no. So no
such thing has happened, but the
Iranians are certainly capable of taking
out a career with multiple missiles. Um,
it would potentially collapse a morale
somewhere. I suppose
Krishant Bordoy says mom Dani should
focus on finding who his dad is.
Very naughty statement you're making
there.
His mommy was married to a gentleman
called epste, right? A different
Epstein, but she was involved in some
way or the other with the epste files.
She her name does figure in that
stash of documents.
Um so yeah I suppose I would uh tend to
agree with you Krishant that Mamani
should focus on finding who his actual
dad is.
Ktos says are Arians and Turks greatest
Eurasian con conquerors.
The greatest conquerors are the people
who belong to this extended family
which carries the mutation genetic
mutation associated with the haplo group
R1 A1A.
Okay, R1 A1A R1 A1A. This is the most
successful extended extended family in
human history.
What does it say? AI uh major ancient Y
chromosome lineage widespread across
Eurasia particularly prevent prevalent
in the Indian subcontinent up to 72% of
Bengali, Brahmin, Gujarati, Lhanas and
Eastern Europe and so on. Okay. So this
is where R1A1A is prevalent. More than 1
billion men today are part of this
extended family and more than 1 billion
men they have they are descended from
one single person who lived about 25
27,000 years ago most likely in the
Indian subcontinent this is the most
successful extended family in human
history the greatest conquerors it is
not a Turk family they call it the Arian
gene which is a very wrong way of saying
things of of of characterizing it but
yes it seems seems to be associated with
the spread of the Indo-Uropean
languages.
So it's definitely not Turk, it's Arian.
Pan Sharma says, "Why are we not able to
build a real Iron Man suit? It is
impossible to produce so much power in
such a compact suit. Why can we not use
nuclear power?" Well, if you want to use
nuclear power, you would need a nuclear
reactor. The best nuclear reactors weigh
several tons.
A human being can't carry something that
weighs several tons. Even 50 kilograms
carrying that is for a long time it's
difficult. Right? And then if you have a
nuclear reactor
h how does a nuclear reactor generate
power? By driving a steam engine.
Okay, a steam engine has a lot of water
and a very high temperature and very
high pressures. How do you fit all of
that into an iron man suit? You can't.
Okay, so that's we're talking about
nuclear fish here. What about nuclear
fusion? Fusion reactors will possibly be
smaller. But in a fusion reactor, you
need to have magnetic confinement of
plasma in a tokamak kind of structure.
How do you fit that into an iron man?
The engineering problems are are
extremely difficult and that's why we're
not able to have an iron man suit. You
can have a battery but then it won't
produce the kind of power you want for
Iron Man, right? A battery silicon
lithium ion battery or sodium ion
battery whatever it can't be the power
you want. So see there are these massive
engineering problems which is why you
can't have an iron man suit. And even if
you have let's say a miniaturized fusion
reactor, how will you fly around? You
will need exhaust. What what kind of
fuel will you use for that? So these
questions, these practical problems
questions, you know, they are the reason
why you can't build an iron iron man
suit with a present day technology.
Dir Kamat says Deepak Chopra was in the
Epstein files. Yes, despicable man. I
saw that uh that twoline email he sent
to Jeffrey Epstein. Des what God is a
what artificial construct or something
but
something about girls or something?
Absolutely despicable man. Deepak Chopra
charlatan
charlatau.
Okay. Uh Katos says how zoroastrian are
Islam, Judaism, Christianity?
They aren't Zoroastrian at all. Islam,
Judaism, Christianity are the three um
Abrahamic religions. Zoroastrianism is
not an Abrahamic religion. It is an
Arian religion. So it's part of a
totally different family of religions.
It has nothing in common with Islam,
Judaism, Christianity. Judaism may have
to some extent been um inspired by
Zuroshianism and I've discussed that in
in in in
previous live streams uh because uh the
Jews they were uh rescued by by the
Persian emperor Cyrus uh when they were
in c captivity in Babylon and Cyrus
Kurrush is the guy who rescued the Jews
and allowed them to go back to Judea and
Israel and they were definitely
influenced by Kurush who Was Cyrus
Zoroastrian? That's a the big question.
Probably Cyrus was not Zoroastrian.
If Zoroast if Zaratusra was born after
the rule of Cyrus
then how does that work? Because before
Zoroastrianism Persia was Hindu. So yeah
so there is the possibility of some
influence of Zorostism Zoroastrianism on
his on on on Judaism.
But how much
maybe to some extent died with
precaution says US not Australia also
are Russian greatest conquers
US not Australia
US not Australia what
also are Russia Russian's greatest
conquerors the Americans are the great
the Anglo-Saxons are the greatest
conquerors
Okay, let's see. Okay. Uh, Ang Ang
Anglosaxon
population
1500. What was it
in 1500? 2 to 2 and a2 million. Okay,
that's the Anglo-Saxon population.
Anglo-Saxon population
2026.
UK 69 million. What about the US? What
about Australia? So in 1500 the
Anglo-Saxon population was about 2
million. Today it is well over
200 or 300 million. Imagine that they
are the greatest conquerors not the
Russians. Okay. Okay, dud to says if
Indian cricket team represents if Indian
cricket team represents sik Hindu Muslim
player as a India team, why can't sick
Muslim and Christians live a normal life
in India? I have no idea. I I don't
know. I I
uh Krishnan Bodaloy says, "Yogi has
suspended 68,000 baboos at the start."
Okay, I'm not aware of this, but okay.
All right. Okay. Harish Sharma says, "Is
super soul soldier serum possible like
Captain America?" I don't know.
I haven't seen Captain America, so I
don't know what happens in Captain
America. Super soldier serum. You mean
some kind of injection that makes you a
superhuman like Spider-Man?
Is it possible? I suppose some of these
things could be possible.
Various drugs are given, I suppose, to
soldiers that make them more capable
than regular people. I suppose it's it's
possible but I'm not sure to what extent
like Captain America because I haven't
seen that. So okay V for Valor says
thank you for your efforts to bring out
the truth. Thank you so much. You're
most welcome. You're very welcome and uh
I do what I can. I try to play my role.
Right. Thank you.
Vipul Pawar says where does semilass
gravity first break down
or semi-classical gravity?
I only know of classical gravity.
I mean we have the Newtonian picture of
gravity and we have the Einsteinian
picture of gravity. The Einsteinian
picture of gravity is called general
relativity. And where does that break
down? It breaks down at the small
scales. General relativity works at the
large scales of the universe. Not the
macro scale of the universe. But it
doesn't work with the at microscopic
scales. uh there are experiments that
have been performed to kind of figure
out to what extent does gravity work at
the smallest scales with for example if
you take dust particles uh do they
behave gravitationally the way you
expect them to behave from a Newtonian
perspective for example so so what are
the limits the limits of the small scale
of classical gravity is what people have
tried to do and uh it's very hard to do
those experiments because the particles
we using are very small and so on but
what we know for sure is that this
breaks down classical gravity breaks
down at the quantum quantum level
quantum domain quantum scales which is
atomic and subatomic scales we know it
breaks down there and we can see the
breakdown in the Einstein field
equations the solutions of the Einstein
field equations which are those
solutions they give rise to
singularities which is a regions inside
and other inside black holes there's
also regularity and so on but we'll talk
about the Schwzchill black hole inside
the the core of the Schwzil black hole
we have a singularity which is a region
of infinite density infinite curve which
is non-physical that's a clear this
clear evidence that the equations have
broken down so it is the best theory we
have Einstein's general relativity but
it is flawed it has a problem and the
problem is very visible in those
singularities so that is what I can tell
you I'm not sure about what other
semiclassical gravity we have I mean um
yeah Hawings solution
um is semi-class right Hawkings solution
which gives rise to Hawking radiation is
semi-classical but yeah that's what I
can tell you okay Vihank Kurana says
given Sanskrit's structured grammar
uh okay one request please stop taking
super chats I'm going to end it now okay
very soon so Vihank says given
Sanskrit's structured grammar and has
system of encoding numbers and verses
could it have applications in modern
cryptography why is knowledge in many
sanatan texts expressed in highly
compact or encoded forms uh there was a
tradition I'm not sure why the tradition
was like that. I mean tradition was that
way. I mean mathematical uh theorems are
encoded in Sanskrit verses essentially
instead of encode representing them in
terms of you know equations like we do
today
and that was one of the reasons why it
was a little hard for a lot of people to
understand mathematics back in the day I
suppose but Sanskrit grammar Sanskrit
grammar is extremely extremely
structured incredibly versatile
incredibly simple as well as incredibly
complex you can encode riddles and
numbers numbers and equations and
theorems in verses, right? You can
encode, you know, uh algorithms for
calculating pi in terms of versus for
example pi, you know, pi pi and so on.
Um so that's how it is. Can it have
applications in modern cryptography? I'm
not sure about that.
Possibly, but I'm not sure. Uh why is
knowledge in many of them texts
expressed in highly compact or encoded
forms? I'm not sure why that is that was
the case but it was that way. Okay. Uh
please once again my request please stop
taking super chats. I need to stop this
live stream in the next 10 minutes
maximum. Uh okay. Aron says you said
Indian education system is the reason
why we have poor quality of people. Is
there a country which has a good
education model that we need to copy or
create better people? Can how can we
change the education system? Learn from
Japan. One example is Japan. I'm not
saying their education system is the
best. It may not be very good at the
higher levels. But Japanese kids, very
little kids are taught what civic sense
is. They taught not to litter. They they
are made to clean up their classroom
every day, which is not like a very
heavy exercise. It's just the practice
of keeping your surroundings neat and
tidy. They're taught how to behave.
They're taught
what is what is not acceptable, what
kind of behavior is not acceptable, how
to be dignified, how to be polite. Those
things are taught to Japanese kids from
the time they are very small from the
first year of schooling essentially. So
that's one example. The higher education
system of Japan is pretty pretty brutal.
I'm not recommending that as a good
example. But in the case of civic sense
and all that, the Japanese education
system does a tremendous job of
instilling the right values and the
right behaviors in little children.
That's why the Japanese people are are
so polite, so dignified and there such
incredible impeccable civic sense in
Japan. That's one example. How do we
change the education system? You do it
one year at a time starting from the
lowest nursery level. It will take you
20 years to revamp the entire system but
you do it and listen I have given the
details in episode 28 whatever it is you
can check out my older episodes of
askabit in which I've given all the
details of what needs to be done and now
people are taking more and more super
chats which means this live stream will
never end
says please explain arian spread out of
India to Europe and formation of
Indo-Uropean cultures religion like Zeus
Thor Peroon etc. Um
so there was this battle that happened
the oldest battle recorded in human
literature in the rigida the battle of
the 10 kings in which king Sudas
defeated a coalition of more than 10
other kings 10 other clans they were
defeated and after the defeat they were
expelled out of India
that was the arian spread out of India
into central Asia eventually to Europe
and they took various
Originally they would have all spoken
various forms of Sanskrit but eventually
they've spread out in in various
geographical regions and then the
languages evolved separately. That's why
the you have all the various
indo-uropean languages that spread out
in the region and then you had various
arian gods being manifested in different
forms. So Ditru
became Zusper became Jupiter became
Thor. But those gods encoded the
elements in them of Indra which is the
hammer and the vajra hammer and the
thunderbolt. So that that's how it
spread out. Abirkar says, "Has Modi been
under pressure to publicly congratulate
an unsigned colonial trade deal? He was
strategically silent for so long. I hope
he gets it fine." Please understand the
difference between words and actions.
Modi sent out a tweet, a nice polite
tweet thanking Donald Trump. Modi has
not signed any trade deal. What
pressure? Obviously, he will be under
American pressure to sign this trade
deal.
But he's not signing it. He's simply
thanking Trump for being a nice person
and blah, whatever.
He's playing to Trump's ego, but he has
not signed any deal. As long as the deal
is not signed, I don't care what Modi
says. Words don't matter. Actions
matter. A signing of a trade deal is an
action. Sending a tweet is words. I
don't care about words. It it's not
important.
Hanisha says, "Did you get a chance to
see tumb?" Not yet. Not yet. Not yet.
I'll let you know when I see it. Thank
you for the reminder, sir. Uh Subjit
Kamar Karmakar says, "How can a man get
power without getting into politics?
By creating your own private army of
very highly trained, dangerous people."
That's how you can get power without
getting into politics. Otherwise you
need to get into politics
or you need to be very well connected
through various ways. There are multiple
ways of getting it. But at the end of
the day power what does it mean? The
ability to
to enforce outcomes, the ability to
compel outcomes that obviously needs
hard power. Okay. Tumb is available on
Amazon Prime. Thank you so much. Noted.
Thank you.
Krishant Boraloy says, "Hindustan
Aeronautics Limited removed from AMCA
private players.
What are my thoughts? I not don't not
know at this point what to think. I've
not studied this in detail exactly
what's happened. Maybe the government
wants private players to come into the
picture. Larsson and Tub bro Tatas or
somebody else. I'm not sure. H doesn't
have the best track record. So maybe
it's a good thing, maybe it's a bad
thing. I don't know at this point. I'll
have to look into that. I've just heard
the news of HL being not part of the AMC
AMCA thing in the future. We'll see
about that. Maybe it's a good thing
perhaps. Maybe. Okay,
this is the last for today. Dirat says
or you can run blackmailing scheme on
the entire political class too. I'm Are
you suggesting something along the
Epstein lines?
Uh well, that's I'm not sure if it makes
you really powerful. Maybe it makes you
a tool of powerful people. Maybe you're
not powerful. You are a tool of powerful
people. Maybe that's what the role
Epstein played. Epstein's role was not
that of a powerful man. It was that of a
man who was a tool of powerful people.
Understand that. Yeah.
Okay. That brings me to the end of all
the questions for today. We have done
almost three and a half hours. So, thank
you so much everybody. It was great fun
and I look forward to seeing you in
Sunday's live stream in which I'll take
as many more questions as possible. So,
thank you so much for all the questions.
It was great fun. Keep learning. Keep
asking questions. The only way to learn
is to ask questions and keep raising
your standards. Don't lower your
standards. Don't do that. Raise your
standards, please. Take care. See you
soon. Bye-bye.